<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<urn:document xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-3" xmlns:dmr="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-report-0-1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:urn="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4">
  <dataType xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="MACAddress">
    <description>All MAC addresses are represented as strings of 12 hexadecimal digits (digits 0-9, letters A-F or a-f) displayed as six pairs of digits separated by colons.  Unspecified or inapplicable MAC addresses MUST be represented as empty strings unless otherwise specified by the parameter definition.</description>
    <string>
      <size maxLength="17"/>
      <pattern value=""/>
      <pattern value="([0-9A-Fa-f][0-9A-Fa-f]:){5}([0-9A-Fa-f][0-9A-Fa-f])"/>
    </string>
  </dataType>
  <dataType xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="IPAddress">
    <description>IP address, i.e. IPv4 address (or IPv4 subnet mask) or IPv6 address.
All IPv4 addresses and subnet masks MUST be represented as strings in IPv4 dotted-decimal notation.  Here are some examples of valid IPv4 address textual representations:
* 216.52.29.100
* 192.168.1.254
All IPv6 addresses MUST be represented using any of the 3 standard textual representations defined in {{bibref|RFC4291}} Sections 2.2.1, 2.2.2 and 2.2.3.  Both lower-case and upper-case letters can be used, but use of lower-case letters is RECOMMENDED.  Here are some examples of valid IPv6 address textual representations:
* 1080:0:0:800:ba98:3210:11aa:12dd
* 1080::800:ba98:3210:11aa:12dd
* 0:0:0:0:0:0:13.1.68.3
IPv6 addresses MUST NOT include zone identifiers. Zone identifiers are discussed in {{bibref|RFC4007|Section 6}}.
Unspecified or inapplicable addresses (or IPv4 subnet masks) MUST be represented as empty strings unless otherwise specified by the parameter definition.</description>
    <string>
      <size maxLength="45"/>
    </string>
  </dataType>
  <model name="InternetGatewayDevice:1.4">
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>The top-level object for an Internet Gateway Device.</description>
      <parameter name="LANDeviceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|LANDevice}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WANDeviceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|WANDevice}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DeviceSummary" access="readOnly" forcedInform="true" dmr:previousParameter="">
        <description action="replace">As defined in {{bibref|TR-106a1}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="1024"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.DeviceInfo." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains general device information.</description>
      <parameter name="Manufacturer" access="readOnly">
        <description>The manufacturer of the CPE (human readable string).</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ManufacturerOUI" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">This value MUST remain fixed over the lifetime of the device, including across firmware updates.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="6"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ModelName" access="readOnly">
        <description>Model name of the CPE (human readable string).</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Description" access="readOnly">
        <description>A full description of the CPE device (human readable string).</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SerialNumber" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">This value MUST remain fixed over the lifetime of the device, including across firmware updates.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="HardwareVersion" access="readOnly" forcedInform="true">
        <description>A string identifying the particular CPE model and version.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SoftwareVersion" access="readOnly" activeNotify="forceEnabled" forcedInform="true">
        <description action="replace">A string identifying the software version currently installed in the CPE.
To allow version comparisons, this element SHOULD be in the form of dot-delimited integers, where each successive integer represents a more minor category of variation.  For example, ''3.0.21'' where the components mean: ''Major.Minor.Build''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SpecVersion" access="readOnly" forcedInform="true" status="deprecated">
        <description action="replace">Represents the version of the specification implemented by the device.  Currently 1.0 is the only available version.  The value of this parameter MUST equal "1.0".
This parameter is DEPRECATED because its value is fixed and it therefore serves no purpose.  However, it is a Forced Inform parameter and therefore cannot be OBSOLETED.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value="1.0" status="deleted"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ProvisioningCode" access="readWrite" activeNotify="forceEnabled" forcedInform="true">
        <description action="replace">Identifier of the primary service provider and other provisioning information, which MAY be used by the ACS to determine service provider-specific customization and provisioning parameters.
If not {{empty}}, this argument SHOULD be in the form of a hierarchical descriptor with one or more nodes specified.  Each node in the hierarchy is represented as a 4-character sub-string, containing only numerals or upper-case letters.  If there is more than one node indicated, each node is separated by a "." (dot).  Examples: "TLCO" or "TLCO.GRP2".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UpTime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Time in seconds since the CPE was last restarted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DeviceLog" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Vendor-specific log(s).</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="32768"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.IPPingDiagnostics." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">This object provides access to an IP-layer ping test.</description>
      <parameter name="DiagnosticsState" access="readWrite" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">Indicates availability of diagnostic data.  {{enum}}
If the ACS sets the value of this parameter to {{enum|Requested}}, the CPE MUST initiate the corresponding diagnostic test.  When writing, the only allowed value is {{enum|Requested}}.  To ensure the use of the proper test parameters (the writable parameters in this object), the test parameters MUST be set either prior to or at the same time as (in the same SetParameterValues) setting the {{param}} to {{enum|Requested}}.
When requested, the CPE SHOULD wait until after completion of the communication session with the ACS before starting the diagnostic.
When the test is completed, the value of this parameter MUST be either {{enum|Complete}} (if the test completed successfully), or one of the ''Error'' values listed above.
If the value of this parameter is anything other than {{enum|Complete}}, the values of the results parameters for this test are indeterminate.
When the diagnostic initiated by the ACS is completed (successfully or not), the CPE MUST establish a new connection to the ACS to allow the ACS to view the results, indicating the Event code ''8 DIAGNOSTICS COMPLETE'' in the Inform message.
After the diagnostic is complete, the value of all result parameters (all read-only parameters in this object) MUST be retained by the CPE until either this diagnostic is run again, or the CPE reboots.  After a reboot, if the CPE has not retained the result parameters from the most recent test, it MUST set the value of this parameter to {{enum|None}}.
Modifying any of the writable parameters in this object except for this one MUST result in the value of this parameter being set to {{enum|None}}.
While the test is in progress, modifying any of the writable parameters in this object except for this one MUST result in the test being terminated and the value of this parameter being set to {{enum|None}}.
While the test is in progress, setting this parameter to {{enum|Requested}} (and possibly modifying other writable parameters in this object) MUST result in the test being terminated and then restarted using the current values of the test parameters.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="None" access="readOnly"/>
            <enumeration value="Requested"/>
            <enumeration value="Complete" access="readOnly"/>
            <enumeration value="Error_CannotResolveHostName" access="readOnly"/>
            <enumeration value="Error_Internal" access="readOnly"/>
            <enumeration value="Error_Other" access="readOnly"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Interface" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">{{reference|the WAN or LAN IP-layer interface over which the test is to be performed}}  This identifies the source IP address to use when performing the test.
The following is a WAN interface example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.1.WANConnectionDevice.2.WANPPPConnection.1''
The following is a LAN interface example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.LANHostConfigManagement.IPInterface.1''
The value of this parameter MUST be either a valid interface or {{empty}}.  An attempt to set this parameter to a different value MUST be rejected as an invalid parameter value.
If {{empty}} is specified, the CPE MUST use the interface as directed by its routing policy (Forwarding table entries) to determine the appropriate interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <pathRef refType="weak" targetType="row"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Host" access="readWrite">
        <description>Host name or address of the host to ping.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="NumberOfRepetitions" access="readWrite">
        <description>Number of repetitions of the ping test to perform before reporting the results.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Timeout" access="readWrite">
        <description>Timeout in milliseconds for the ping test.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DataBlockSize" access="readWrite">
        <description>Size of the data block in bytes to be sent for each ping.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="65535"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DSCP" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">DiffServ codepoint to be used for the test packets.  By default the CPE SHOULD set this value to zero.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="0" maxInclusive="63"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SuccessCount" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Result parameter indicating the number of successful pings (those in which a successful response was received prior to the timeout) in the most recent ping test.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FailureCount" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Result parameter indicating the number of failed pings in the most recent ping test.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AverageResponseTime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Result parameter indicating the average response time in milliseconds over all repetitions with successful responses of the most recent ping test.  If there were no successful responses, this value MUST be zero.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaximumResponseTime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Result parameter indicating the maximum response time in milliseconds over all repetitions with successful responses of the most recent ping test.  If there were no successful responses, this value MUST be zero.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MinimumResponseTime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Result parameter indicating the minimum response time in milliseconds over all repetitions with successful responses of the most recent ping test.  If there were no successful responses, this value MUST be zero.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANConfigSecurity." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains generic device configuration information.</description>
      <parameter name="ConfigPassword" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">A password to allow LAN access to protected auto-configuration services.
If the CPE supports TR-064 (LAN-side DSL CPE Configuration Protocol), this parameter is to be used as the ''dslf-config'' password (as defined in TR-064).
If the CPE has a user interface with password protection enabled, this parameter is also to be used as the user password for password-protected operations.  However, this parameter MUST NOT be used to set the user password if the parameter {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.UserInterface.PasswordUserSelectable}} is {{true}}.</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="LANDeviceNumberOfEntries">
      <description action="replace">Each instance models a LAN side layer 3 IP interface.
Each instance has children that correspond to the layer 2 interfaces that are connected to the Gateway's IP router via the modeled IP interface.  If a LANDevice instance is deleted, the objects modeling those layer 2 interfaces that are as a result no longer connected to the Gateway's IP router will move to the InternetGatewayDevice.LANInterfaces object.
If the ''Layer2Bridging'' object is implemented, the view that it provides of the CPE's underlying bridging configuration MUST be consistent with the view provided by any ''LANDevice'' and ''WAN**Connection'' objects.  The implications of this are explained in {{bibref|TR-098a2|Annex A.6}}.</description>
      <parameter name="LANEthernetInterfaceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|LANEthernetInterfaceConfig}} in this ''LANDevice''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LANUSBInterfaceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|LANUSBInterfaceConfig}} in this ''LANDevice''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LANWLANConfigurationNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|WLANConfiguration}} in this ''LANDevice''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.Hosts." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object provides information about each of the hosts on the LAN, including those whose IP address was allocated by the CPE using DHCP as well as hosts with statically allocated IP addresses.</description>
      <parameter name="HostNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of entries in the {{object|Host}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.Hosts.Host.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="HostNumberOfEntries">
      <description>Host table.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="MACAddress"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="IPAddress" access="readOnly">
        <description>Current IP Address of the host.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AddressSource" access="readOnly">
        <description>Indicates whether the IP address of the host was allocated by the CPE using DHCP, was assigned to the host statically, or was assigned using automatic IP address allocation.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="DHCP"/>
            <enumeration value="Static"/>
            <enumeration value="AutoIP"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LeaseTimeRemaining" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">DHCP lease time remaining in seconds.  A value of -1 indicates an infinite lease.  The value MUST be 0 (zero) if the {{param|AddressSource}} is not {{enum|DHCP|AddressSource}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int>
            <range minInclusive="-1"/>
          </int>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddress" access="readOnly">
        <description>MAC address of the host.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="MACAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="HostName" access="readOnly">
        <description>The device's host name or {{empty}} if unknown.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InterfaceType" access="readOnly">
        <description>Type of physical interface through which this host is connected to the CPE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Ethernet"/>
            <enumeration value="USB"/>
            <enumeration value="802.11"/>
            <enumeration value="HomePNA"/>
            <enumeration value="HomePlug"/>
            <enumeration value="MoCA"/>
            <enumeration value="Other"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Active" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Whether or not the host is currently present on the LAN.  The method of presence detection is a local matter to the CPE.
The ability to list inactive hosts is OPTIONAL.  If the CPE includes inactive hosts in this table, this variable MUST be set to {{false}} for each inactive host.  The length of time an inactive host remains listed in this table is a local matter to the CPE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Layer2Interface" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="MACAddress">
        <description>This parameter is the full hierarchical parameter name of a particular ''LAN**InterfaceConfig'' object or a ''WLANConfiguration'' object.  For example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.LANEthernetInterfaceConfig.2''.
In the case of an embedded Ethernet switch, the {{param}} parameter references the ''LANEthernetInterfaceConfig'' object that corresponds to the switch port the device is connected to (a ''LANEthernetInterfaceConfig'' instance for each switch port).
In the case of an embedded WLAN access point, the {{param}} parameter references the ''WLANConfiguration'' object that corresponds to the SSID the device is connected to (if the access point supports multiple SSIDs, then each SSID is a separate instance).</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANEthernetInterfaceConfig.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="LANEthernetInterfaceNumberOfEntries">
      <description action="replace">This object models an Ethernet LAN connection on a CPE device.  This object MUST be implemented for CPE that contain an Ethernet interface on the LAN side.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="MACAddress"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Status" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The {{enum|Error}} value MAY be used by the CPE to indicate a locally defined error condition.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Up"/>
            <enumeration value="NoLink"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddress" access="readOnly">
        <description>The physical address of the interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="MACAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddressControlEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description>Indicates whether MAC Address Control is enabled or not on this interface.  MAC Address Control limits the clients that connect to those that match a list of allowed MAC addresses specified in {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANHostConfigManagement.AllowedMACAddresses}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxBitRate" access="readWrite">
        <description>The maximum upstream and downstream bit rate available to this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="10"/>
            <enumeration value="100"/>
            <enumeration value="1000"/>
            <enumeration value="10000"/>
            <enumeration value="Auto"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DuplexMode" access="readWrite">
        <description>The duplex mode available to this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Half"/>
            <enumeration value="Full"/>
            <enumeration value="Auto"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Name" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="Status">
        <description>The name of this layer 2 interface, chosen by the vendor, e.g. "eth0" or "eth0:1".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="16"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANEthernetInterfaceConfig.{i}.Stats." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="append">Note that these statistics refer to the link layer, not to the physical layer.</description>
      <parameter name="BytesSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes transmitted out of the interface, including framing characters. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BytesReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes received on the interface, including framing characters. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets transmitted out of the interface.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets which were received on this interface.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ErrorsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets that could not be transmitted because of errors. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ErrorsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets that contained errors preventing them from being deliverable. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UnicastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address, including those that were discarded or not sent. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UnicastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DiscardPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being transmitted.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DiscardPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being deliverable.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MulticastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were addressed to a multicast address, including those that were discarded or not sent.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MulticastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a multicast address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BroadcastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were addressed to a broadcast address, including those that were discarded or not sent.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BroadcastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a broadcast address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UnknownProtoPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets received via the interface which were discarded because of an unknown or unsupported protocol.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANHostConfigManagement." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="append">The DHCP parameters in this object define the behavior of the default DHCP server, i.e. the behavior for DHCP requests that do not match any of the DHCP conditional serving pool entries.</description>
      <parameter name="DHCPServerConfigurable" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Enables the configuration of the DHCP server on the LAN interface.  If this variable is set to {{false}}, the CPE SHOULD restore its default DHCP server settings.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="true"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DHCPServerEnable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the DHCP server on the LAN interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DHCPRelay" access="readOnly" status="deprecated">
        <description action="replace">Indicates if the DHCP server performs the role of a server ({{false}}) or a relay ({{true}}) on the LAN interface.
This parameter is DEPRECATED because the functionality that it describes is not well-defined.  The CPE MAY set it to the value that it thinks most appropriate, based on its configuration.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MinAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">This parameter MUST have a valid value before the DHCP server can be enabled.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">This parameter MUST have a valid value before the DHCP server can be enabled.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ReservedAddresses" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Addresses marked reserved from the address allocation pool.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SubnetMask" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">This parameter MUST have a valid value before the DHCP server can be enabled.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DNSServers" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">DNS servers offered to DHCP clients.  Support for more than three DNS Servers is OPTIONAL.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </list>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DomainName" access="readWrite">
        <description>Sets the domain name to provide to clients on the LAN interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="IPRouters" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">IP addresses of routers on this subnet.  Also known as default gateway.  Support for more than one Router address is OPTIONAL.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </list>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="IPInterfaceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">The number of entries in the {{object|IPInterface}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddress" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="">
        <description>The MAC address associated with the IP interface modeled by this LANDevice instance.  This is the MAC address that is returned in response to an ARP request for any of the IP interface's IP addresses.  It is also the source MAC address in all IP traffic sent over the IP interface.
If no single MAC address meets the above criteria, the value of this parameter MUST be the all-zero MAC address ''00:00:00:00:00:00''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="MACAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>The number of entries in the {{object|DHCPOption}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANHostConfigManagement.DHCPConditionalServingPool.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="DHCPConditionalPoolNumberOfEntries">
      <description>DHCP conditional serving pool table.
Each instance of this object defines a DHCP conditional serving pool.  Client requests are associated with pools based on criteria such as source interface, supplied DHCP options, and MAC address.
If a DHCP request does not match any of the DHCP conditional serving pool entries, the handling of the request is determined by the default DHCP server behavior that is defined by the LANHostConfigManagement object.
Overlapping pool ranges MUST be supported.</description>
      <parameter name="DHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>The number of entries in the {{object|DHCPOption}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANHostConfigManagement.DHCPConditionalServingPool.{i}.DHCPOption.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="DHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description>This object specifies the DHCP options that MUST, if enabled, be returned to clients whose DHCP requests are associated with this pool.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="Tag"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this DHCPOption table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Tag" access="readWrite">
        <description>Option tag as defined in RFC 2132 {{bibref|RFC2132}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="254"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Value" access="readWrite">
        <description>Base64 encoded option value.</description>
        <syntax>
          <base64>
            <size minLength="0" maxLength="255"/>
          </base64>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANHostConfigManagement.DHCPOption.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="DHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description>This object specifies the DHCP options that MUST, if enabled, be returned to clients whose DHCP requests do not match any of the DHCP conditional serving pool entries.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="Tag"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this DHCPOption table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Tag" access="readWrite">
        <description>Option tag as defined in RFC 2132 {{bibref|RFC2132}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="254"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Value" access="readWrite">
        <description>Base64 encoded option value.</description>
        <syntax>
          <base64>
            <size minLength="0" maxLength="255"/>
          </base64>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANHostConfigManagement.IPInterface.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="IPInterfaceNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description action="replace">IP address table with each object representing an IP address on the LANDevice IP interface.
Support for more than one interface instance is OPTIONAL.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="IPInterfaceIPAddress"/>
        <parameter ref="IPInterfaceSubnetMask"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this entry.  On creation, an entry is disabled by default.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="IPInterfaceIPAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description>IP address of the LAN-side interface of the CPE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="IPInterfaceSubnetMask" access="readWrite">
        <description>Subnet mask of the LAN-side interface of the IGD.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="IPInterfaceAddressingType" access="readWrite">
        <description>Represents the addressing method used to assign the LAN-side IP address of the CPE on this interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="DHCP"/>
            <enumeration value="Static"/>
            <enumeration value="AutoIP"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value="DHCP"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="LANWLANConfigurationNumberOfEntries">
      <description action="replace">This object models an 802.11 LAN connection on a CPE device.  This object MUST be implemented for CPE that contain an 802.11 interface on the LAN side.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="BSSID"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="SSID"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">When there are multiple ''WLANConfiguration'' instances, e.g. each instance supports a different 802.11 standard or has a different security configuration, this parameter can be used to control which of the instances are currently enabled.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Status" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The {{enum|Error}} value MAY be used by the CPE to indicate a locally defined error condition.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Up"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BSSID" access="readOnly">
        <description>The MAC address of the interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxBitRate" access="readWrite">
        <description>The maximum upstream and downstream bit rate available to this connection in Mbps.  Either ''Auto'', or the largest of the {{param|OperationalDataTransmitRates}} values.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="4"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Channel" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The current radio channel used by the connection.  To request automatic channel selection, set {{param|AutoChannelEnable}} to {{true}}.
Whenever {{param|AutoChannelEnable}} is {{true}}, the value of the {{param}} parameter MUST be the channel selected by the automatic channel selection procedure.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="0" maxInclusive="255"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SSID" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The current service set identifier in use by the connection.  The SSID is an identifier that is attached to packets sent over the wireless LAN that functions as a "password" for joining a particular radio network (BSS).  Note: If an access point wishes to be known by more than one SSID, it MUST provide a ''WLANConfiguration'' instance for each SSID.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="32"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BeaconType" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The capabilities that are currently enabled on the access point (and that are announced via beacons if {{param|BeaconAdvertisementEnabled}} is {{true}}). Write access to this parameter enables and disables such capabilities.
An attempt to set this parameter to one of the REQUIRED (mandatory) values MAY be rejected if (and only if) the requested capability is not available on this WLANConfiguration instance but is available on another WLANConfiguration instance within this Internet Gateway Device. For example, only basic 802.11 might be supported by one virtual AP, and only WPA might be supported by another virtual AP.
A value of {{enum|None}} means that no capabilities are currently enabled on the access point and that no stations will be able to associate with it.  {{enum}}
{{enum|11i}} SHOULD be taken to refer to both the 802.11i specification and to the WPA2 specification (any WPA2-certified device will implement all mandatory parts of the 802.11i standard).
The OBSOLETED values are those for Basic + WPA/WPA2  mixed modes, which are not permitted by the WPA specifications.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="None"/>
            <enumeration value="Basic"/>
            <enumeration value="WPA"/>
            <enumeration value="11i" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="BasicandWPA" status="obsoleted" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="Basicand11i" status="obsoleted" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="WPAand11i" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="BasicandWPAand11i" status="obsoleted" optional="true"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddressControlEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description>Indicates whether MAC Address Control is enabled or not on this interface.  MAC Address Control limits the clients that connect to those that match a list of allowed MAC addresses specified in {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.LANHostConfigManagement.AllowedMACAddresses}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Standard" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Indicates which IEEE 802.11 standard this ''WLANConfiguration'' instance is configured for.  {{enum}}
Where each value indicates support for only the indicated standard.
If the device is configured simultaneously for more than one standard, a separate ''WLANConfiguration'' instance MUST be used for each supported standard.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="a"/>
            <enumeration value="b"/>
            <enumeration value="g">
              <description action="replace">b and g clients supported</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="g-only">
              <description>only g clients supported</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="n"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WEPKeyIndex" access="readWrite">
        <description>The index of the default WEP key.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="4"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="KeyPassphrase" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">A passphrase from which the WEP keys are to be generated.
This parameter is the same as the parameter ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.PreSharedKey.1.KeyPassphrase'' for the same instance of ''WLANConfiguration''.  When either parameter is changed, the value of the other is changed as well.
If {{param}} is written, all four WEP keys are immediately generated.  The ACS SHOULD NOT set the passphrase and also set the WEP keys directly (the result of doing this is undefined).
This MUST either be a valid key length divided by 8, in which case each byte contributes 8 bits to the key, or else MUST consist of Hex digits and be a valid key length divided by 4, in which case each byte contributes 4 bits to the key.
Note: If a passphrase is used, all four WEP keys will be the same.</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="63"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WEPEncryptionLevel" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Supported key lengths.  {{enum}}
Any additional vendor-specific values MUST start with the key length in bits.
This parameter does not enforce a given encryption level but only indicates capabilities.  The WEP encryption level for a given key is inferred from the key length.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </list>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
            <enumeration value="40-bit"/>
            <enumeration value="104-bit"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BasicEncryptionModes" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
If this ''WLANConfiguration'' instance does not support basic 802.11 then this parameter MUST NOT be present in this instance of the ''WLANConfiguration'' object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="31" status="deleted"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BasicAuthenticationMode" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
If this ''WLANConfiguration'' instance does not support basic 802.11 then this parameter MUST NOT be present in this instance of the ''WLANConfiguration'' object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="31" status="deleted"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WPAEncryptionModes" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
If this ''WLANConfiguration'' instance does not support WPA then this parameter MUST NOT be present in this instance of the ''WLANConfiguration'' object.
The DEPRECATED values are those that combine WEP with TKIP and/or AES, which is not permitted by the WPA specifications.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="31" status="deleted"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WPAAuthenticationMode" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
If this ''WLANConfiguration'' instance does not support WPA then this parameter MUST NOT be present in this instance of the ''WLANConfiguration'' object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="31" status="deleted"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PossibleChannels" access="readOnly">
        <description>Possible radio channels for the wireless standard (a, b or g) and the regulatory domain. 
Ranges in the form "n-m" are permitted.
For example, for 802.11b and North America, would be "1-11".</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="1024"/>
          </list>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BasicDataTransmitRates" access="readWrite">
        <description>Maximum access point data transmit rates in Mbps for unicast, multicast and broadcast frames.
For example, a value of "1,2", indicates that unicast, multicast and broadcast frames can be transmitted at 1 Mbps and 2 Mbps.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </list>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="OperationalDataTransmitRates" access="readWrite">
        <description>Maximum access point data transmit rates in Mbps for unicast frames (a superset of {{param|BasicDataTransmitRates}}).
Given the value of {{param|BasicDataTransmitRates}} from the example above, {{param}} might be "1,2,5.5,11", indicating that unicast frames can additionally be transmitted at 5.5 Mbps and 11 Mbps.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </list>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PossibleDataTransmitRates" access="readOnly">
        <description>Data transmit rates for unicast frames at which the access point will permit a station to connect (a subset of {{param|OperationalDataTransmitRates}}).
Given the values of {{param|BasicDataTransmitRates}} and {{param|OperationalDataTransmitRates}} from the examples above, {{param}} might be "1,2,5.5", indicating that the AP will only permit connections at 1 Mbps, 2 Mbps and 5.5 Mbps, even though it could theoretically accept connections at 11 Mbps.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </list>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RadioEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description>Indicates whether or not the access point radio is enabled.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AutoRateFallBackEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description>Indicates whether the access point can automatically reduce the data rate in the event of undue noise or contention.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalBytesSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes transmitted out of the interface, including framing characters. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalBytesReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes received on the interface, including framing characters. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets transmitted out of the interface.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets which were received on this interface.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalAssociations" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The number of devices currently associated with the access point.  This corresponds to the number of entries in the AssociatedDevice table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Name" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="Status">
        <description>The name of this layer 2 interface, chosen by the vendor, e.g. "wlan0".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="16"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AutoChannelEnable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enable or disable automatic channel selection.
Set to {{false}} to disable the automatic channel selection procedure, in which case the currently selected channel remains selected.
Set to {{true}} to enable the automatic channel selection procedure.  This procedure MUST automatically select the channel, and MAY also change it subsequently.
{{param}} MUST automatically change to {{false}} whenever the channel is manually selected, i.e. whenever the {{param|Channel}} parameter is written.
Whenever {{param}} is {{true}}, the value of the {{param|Channel}} parameter MUST be the channel selected by the automatic channel selection procedure.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SSIDAdvertisementEnabled" access="readWrite" dmr:previousParameter="BeaconAdvertisementEnabled">
        <description>Indicates whether or not beacons include the SSID name.
This parameter has an effect only if {{param|BeaconAdvertisementEnabled}} is {{true}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TransmitPowerSupported" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="RadioEnabled">
        <description>Supported transmit power levels as percentages of full power.  For example, "0,25,50,75,100".</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </list>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="0" maxInclusive="100"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TransmitPower" access="readWrite">
        <description>Indicates the current transmit power level as a percentage of full power.  The value MUST be one of the values reported by the {{param|TransmitPowerSupported}} parameter.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="0" maxInclusive="100"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.AssociatedDevice.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="TotalAssociations">
      <description action="replace">A table of the devices currently associated with the access point.  The size of this table is given by {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.TotalAssociations}}.  This object MUST be implemented for CPE that contain an 802.11 interface on the LAN side.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="AssociatedDeviceMACAddress"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="AssociatedDeviceMACAddress" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The MAC address of an associated device.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="MACAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AssociatedDeviceIPAddress" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The IP address or DNS name of an associated device.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AssociatedDeviceAuthenticationState" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Whether an associated device has authenticated ({{true}}) or not ({{false}}).</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.PreSharedKey.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="10" maxEntries="10">
      <description action="replace">This is a table of preshared keys.  The size of this table is fixed with exactly 10 entries (with instance numbers 1 through 10).  This object MUST be implemented for CPE that contain an 802.11 interface on the LAN side.</description>
      <parameter name="PreSharedKey" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">A literal WPA PSK expressed as a hexadecimal string.
The first table entry contains the default {{param}} (''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.PreSharedKey.1.PreSharedKey'').
If {{param|KeyPassphrase}} is written, the PSK is immediately generated.  The ACS SHOULD NOT set the passphrase and also set the PSK directly (the result of doing this is undefined).</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="KeyPassphrase" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">A passphrase from which the PSK is to be generated.
The first table entry is the same as the parameter {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.KeyPassphrase}} for the same instance of WLANConfiguration.  When either parameter is changed, the value of the other is changed as well.
If {{param}} is written, the PSK is immediately generated.  The ACS SHOULD NOT set the passphrase and also set the PSK directly (the result of doing this is undefined).
The key is generated as specified by WPA, which uses PBKDF2 from PKCS #5: Password-based Cryptography Specification Version 2.0 (RFC 2898 {{bibref|RFC2898}}).</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="63"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.Stats." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains statistics for an 802.11 LAN interface on a CPE device.
Note that these statistics refer to the link layer, not to the physical layer.
Note that this object does not include the total byte and packet statistics, which are, for historical reasons, in the parent object.</description>
      <parameter name="ErrorsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets that could not be transmitted because of errors. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ErrorsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets that contained errors preventing them from being deliverable. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UnicastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address, including those that were discarded or not sent. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UnicastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DiscardPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being transmitted.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DiscardPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being deliverable.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MulticastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were addressed to a multicast address, including those that were discarded or not sent.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MulticastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a multicast address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BroadcastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were addressed to a broadcast address, including those that were discarded or not sent.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BroadcastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a broadcast address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UnknownProtoPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets received via the interface which were discarded because of an unknown or unsupported protocol.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.WEPKey.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="4" maxEntries="4">
      <description action="replace">This is a table of WEP keys.  The size of this table is fixed with exactly 4 entries (with instance numbers 1 through 4).  This object MUST be implemented for CPE that contain an 802.11 interface on the LAN side.</description>
      <parameter name="WEPKey" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">A WEP key expressed as a hexadecimal string. 
The WEP encryption level for a given key is inferred from the key length, e.g. 10 characters for 40-bit encryption, or 26 characters for 104-bit encryption (keys do not all have to be of the same length, although they will be if the CPE uses {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.KeyPassphrase}} to generate them).
If {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.WLANConfiguration.{i}.KeyPassphrase}} is written, all four WEP keys are immediately generated.  The ACS SHOULD NOT set the passphrase and also set the WEP keys directly (the result of doing this is undefined).</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="128"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.LANInterfaces." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains LAN-side layer 1/2 interfaces that are not currently connected to the Gateway's IP router and which therefore do not currently reside within a ''LANDevice'' instance.</description>
      <parameter name="LANEthernetInterfaceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|LANEthernetInterfaceConfig}} in this object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LANUSBInterfaceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|LANUSBInterfaceConfig}} in this object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LANWLANConfigurationNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|WLANConfiguration}} in this object object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Layer2Bridging." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">Layer 2 bridging configuration.  Specifies bridges between layer 2 LAN and/or WAN interfaces.  Bridges can be defined to include layer 2 filter criteria to selectively bridge traffic between interfaces.
This object can be used to configure both 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} and 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} bridges.  Not all 802.1D and 802.1Q features are modeled, and some additional features not present in either 802.1D or 802.1Q are modeled. 
If the Layer2Bridging object is implemented, the view that it provides of the CPE's underlying bridging configuration MUST be consistent with the view provided by any LANDevice and WAN**Connection objects.  The implications of this are explained in Annex A.6.</description>
      <parameter name="MaxBridgeEntries" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The maximum number of entries available in the {{object|Bridge}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxFilterEntries" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The maximum number of entries available in the {{object|Filter}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxMarkingEntries" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The maximum number of entries available in the {{object|Marking}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BridgeNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of entries in the {{object|Bridge}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FilterNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of entries in the {{object|Filter}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MarkingNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of entries in the {{object|Marking}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AvailableInterfaceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Number of entries in the {{object|AvailableInterface}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxDBridgeEntries" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="MaxBridgeEntries">
        <description>The maximum number of 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} entries available in the {{object|Bridge}} table.  A positive value for this parameter implies support for 802.1D.
There is no guarantee that this many 802.1D Bridges can be configured.  For example, the CPE might not be able simultaneously to support both 802.1D and 802.1Q Bridges.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxQBridgeEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>The maximum number of 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} entries available in the {{object|Bridge}} table.  A positive value for this parameter implies support for 802.1Q.
There is no guarantee that this many 802.1Q Bridges can be configured.  For example, the CPE might not be able simultaneously to support both 802.1D and 802.1Q Bridges.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Layer2Bridging.AvailableInterface.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="AvailableInterfaceNumberOfEntries">
      <description action="replace">Table containing all LAN and WAN interfaces that are available to be referenced by the Bridge table.  Only interfaces that can carry layer 2 bridged traffic are included.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="AvailableInterfaceKey"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="AvailableInterfaceKey" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Unique key for each Interface entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InterfaceType" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Whether the interface is a LAN-side or WAN-side interface, or a LAN-side or WAN-side connection to the Gateway's IP router.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="LANInterface"/>
            <enumeration value="WANInterface"/>
            <enumeration value="LANRouterConnection"/>
            <enumeration value="WANRouterConnection"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InterfaceReference" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">{{reference|an available LAN or WAN interface}}  This table SHOULD contain a single entry for each available LAN and WAN interface.
When such an interface is modeled in more than one place within the data model, the value of this parameter MUST include the full hierarchical parameter names of all of the corresponding objects.  For example, if a given Ethernet interface is present within two ''LANDevice'' instances, the value of this parameter might be: ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.LANEthernetInterfaceConfig.1, InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.2.LANEthernetInterfaceConfig.1''
Note that the remainder of the parameter description does not refer to the possibility that the parameter value is a comma-separated list.  Nevertheless, the above requirement does apply.
* For a WAN interface, this parameter is the full hierarchical parameter name of a particular ''WANConnectionDevice''.  A ''WANConnectionDevice'' is considered available (included in this table) only if it supports layer 2 bridged traffic.  That is, this table MUST include only ''WANConnectionDevice''s that contain either a ''WANEthernetLinkConfig'' object, or that contain a ''WANDSLLinkConfig'' object for which the ''LinkType'' is ''EoA''.  For example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.1.WANConnectionDevice.2''
* For a LAN interface, this parameter is the full hierarchical parameter name of a particular ''LAN**InterfaceConfig'' object, or a ''WLANConfiguration'' object.  This table SHOULD include one entry for each such object.  For example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.LANEthernetInterfaceConfig.2''
* For a WAN-side connection to the Gateway's IP router, this parameter is the full hierarchical parameter name of a particular ''WAN**Connection'' service.  This table SHOULD include an entry for each layer 3 WAN connection.  For example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.1.WANConnectionDevice.2.WANPPPConnection.1''
* For a LAN-side connection to the Gateway's IP router, this parameter is the full hierarchical parameter name of a particular ''LANDevice''.  This table SHOULD include an entry for each ''LANDevice'', each of which is associated with a LAN-side layer 3 connection to the Gateway's IP router.  For example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.2''</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </list>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256" status="deleted"/>
            <pathRef refType="weak" targetType="row"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Layer2Bridging.Bridge.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="BridgeNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="BridgeEnable">
      <description action="replace">Bridge table.  Each entry in this table represents a single physical 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} or 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} bridge.
If the Bridge Port table is supported, it explicitly defines the Bridge's interfaces.  Otherwise, they are implicitly defined via the union of the FilterInterface / MarkingInterface parameters for all the Filter and Marking table entries that are associated with the Bridge.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="BridgeKey"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="BridgeKey" access="readOnly">
        <description>Unique key for each Bridge table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BridgeEnable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this Bridge table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BridgeStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The {{enum|Error}} value MAY be used by the CPE to indicate a locally defined error condition.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Enabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BridgeName" access="readWrite">
        <description>Human-readable name for this Bridge table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="VLANID" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">For an 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} Bridge, which has no concept of VLANs, the value of this parameter MUST be 0.
For an 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} Bridge, this is the Bridge's default VLAN ID, i.e. the VLAN ID that applies to Filter table entries with ''VLANIDFilter''=-1.  For an 802.1Q Bridge, the value of this parameter MUST NOT be 0.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0" status="deleted"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BridgeStandard" access="readWrite" dmr:previousParameter="BridgeKey">
        <description>Selects the standard supported by this Bridge table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="802.1D">
              <description>{{bibref|802.1D-2004}}</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="802.1Q">
              <description>{{bibref|802.1Q-2005}}</description>
            </enumeration>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value="802.1D"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Layer2Bridging.Filter.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="FilterNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="FilterEnable">
      <description action="append">For both 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} and 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} Bridges, this table is used for the following:
# If the Bridge Port table is not supported, it implicitly specifies the Bridge interfaces (in collaboration with the Marking table).
# It specifies destination MAC address classification rules.
For an 802.1Q Bridge, this table is also used for the following:
# For each VLAN ID, it specifies the interfaces that are in the VLAN's Member Set.
# If the Bridge Port table is not supported, it specifies the Port VLAN ID (PVID) for each interface.
This table also supports several concepts that are not covered by either 802.1D or 802.1Q:
# It allows a given packet to be admitted to multiple Bridges.
# It supports Ethertype and source MAC address classification rules.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="FilterKey"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="FilterKey" access="readOnly">
        <description>Unique key for each Filter table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FilterEnable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this Filter table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FilterStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">If the Bridge Port table is supported, but none of its entries correspond to {{param|FilterInterface}}, or if such an entry exists but is disabled, {{param}} MUST NOT indicate {{enum|Enabled}}.
If the Bridge VLAN table is supported, but none of its entries correspond to {{param|VLANIDFilter}}, or if such an entry exists but is disabled, {{param}} MUST NOT indicate {{enum|Enabled}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Enabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FilterBridgeReference" access="readWrite">
        <description>The ''BridgeKey'' value of the ''Bridge'' table entry associated with this Filter.  A value of -1 indicates the Filter table entry is not associated with a Bridge (and has no effect).</description>
        <syntax>
          <int>
            <range minInclusive="-1"/>
          </int>
          <default type="object" value="-1"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ExclusivityOrder" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Whether or not the Filter definition is exclusive of all others.  And if the entry is exclusive, order of precedence.
A value of 1 or greater indicates an Exclusive Filter, where the value 1 indicates the first entry to be considered (highest precedence).
A value of 0 indicates a Non-Exclusive Filter (OPTIONAL).
For each packet, if the packet matches any Exclusive Filters, the packet is assigned to the Bridge associated with the highest precedence Exclusive Filter to which it matches (lowest {{param}} value).
If and only if the packet does not match any Exclusive Filters, the packet is assigned to all Bridges associated with each Non-Exclusive Filter for which it matches the defining criteria.
If a packet matches no Filter, it is discarded.
When the {{param}} is set to match that of an existing Exclusive Filter (1 or greater), the value for the existing entry and all higher numbered entries is incremented (lowered in precedence) to ensure uniqueness of this value. A deletion or change in {{param}} of an Exclusive Filter causes {{param}} values of other Exclusive Filters (values 1 or greater) to be compacted.
Note that the use of Exclusive Filters to associate a layer 3 router interface with LAN and/or WAN interfaces via a Bridge entry overrides and updates the association between layer 3 and layer 2 objects implied by the ''InternetGatewayDevice'' object hierarchy.
Support for Non-Exclusive Filter entries, i.e. entries with an {{param}} value of 0, is OPTIONAL because 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} and 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} do not consider the case of a packet potentially being admitted to more than one bridge.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value="0" status="deleted"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FilterInterface" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The interface or interfaces associated with this Filter table entry.  The bridge corresponding to this Filter table entry is defined to admit packets on ingress to the bridge from the specified interfaces that meet all of the criteria specified in the Filter table entry.  The following values are defined.
* To associate this Filter with a single interface listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table, the {{param}} value is set to the value of the corresponding ''AvailableInterfaceKey''.
* ''AllInterfaces'' indicates that this Filter is associated with all LAN and WAN interfaces listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table (all entries of ''InterfaceType'' ''LANInterface'' or ''WANInterface'').  This value is DEPRECATED because of the configuration complexity it requires.
* ''LANInterfaces'' indicates that this Filter is associated with all LAN interfaces listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table (all entries of ''InterfaceType'' ''LANInterface'').  This value is DEPRECATED because of the configuration complexity it requires.
* ''WANInterfaces'' indicates that this Filter is associated with all WAN interfaces listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table (all entries of ''InterfaceType'' ''WANInterface'').  This value is DEPRECATED because of the configuration complexity it requires.
{{empty}} indicates the Filter table entry is not associated with any interface (and has no effect)</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="16"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="VLANIDFilter" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} VLAN ID associated with this Filter table entry.
A value of -1 indicates that the default VLAN ID for the Bridge MUST be used instead (as specified by {{param|InternetGatewayDevice.Layer2Bridging.Bridge.{i}.VLANID}} for the Bridge table entry associated with this Filter table entry).
For an 802.1Q bridge, the value of this parameter MUST NOT be 0, and it is interpreted as follows  (more than one condition can apply, e.g. a single Filter table entry might both add an interface to a VLAN's Member Set, and define a classification rule).
# If the Bridge Port table is not supported, it is a candidate to be the 802.1Q Port VLAN ID (PVID) for the interface associated with this Filter.  Where there is more than one such candidate for a given interface, the PVID MUST be selected according to the {{param|ExclusivityOrder}} precedence rules.
# The interface associated with this Filter is added to the VLAN's 802.1Q Member Set.
# If a classification parameter, e.g. {{param|DestMACAddressFilterList}}, is specified, a classification rule for this VLAN ID is added.
For an 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} Bridge, which has no concept of VLANs, the VLAN ID MUST be 0.  This is most easily achieved by allowing this parameter to retain its default value of -1 and relying on the fact that the default VLAN ID for an 802.1D bridge will always be 0.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int>
            <range minInclusive="-1" maxInclusive="4094"/>
          </int>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AdmitOnlyVLANTagged" access="readWrite" status="deprecated">
        <description action="replace">802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} Acceptable Frame Types criterion.
This parameter is DEPRECATED, because it only partly models 802.1Q Acceptable Frame Types (and Ingress Filtering).  The Bridge Port table SHOULD be used instead and, if supported, MUST take precedence over this parameter.
If {{true}}, the Bridge admits only packets tagged with VLAN IDs that include the ingress interface in their 802.1Q Member Sets.
If {{false}}, the Bridge admits both packets tagged with VLAN IDs that include the ingress interface in their 802.1Q Member Sets, and any Untagged or PriorityOnly packets.  All Untagged or PriorityOnly packets are associated on ingress with the interface's Port VLAN ID (PVID).
See the description of {{param|VLANIDFilter}} for an explanation of how the Member Set and PVID are determined.
If more than one Filter table entry is associated with a given interface, the value of {{param}} MUST be the same for all such entries.
For an 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} Bridge, which has no concept of VLANs, the value of this parameter MUST be {{false}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthertypeFilterList" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Classification criterion.
{{list|each representing an Ethertype value}}
Note that neither 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} nor 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} support classification based on Ethertype.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </list>
          <unsignedInt/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthertypeFilterExclude" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">Note that neither 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} nor 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} support classification based on Ethertype.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="true"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SourceMACAddressFilterList" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Classification criterion.
{{list|each representing a MAC Address}}
Each list entry MAY optionally specify a bit-mask, where matching of a packet's MAC address is only to be done for bit positions set to one in the mask.  If no mask is specified, all bits of the MAC Address are to be used for matching.
For example, the list might be: ''01:02:03:04:05:06, 1:22:33:00:00:00/FF:FF:FF:00:00:00, 88:77:66:55:44:33''
Note that neither 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} nor 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} support classification based on source MAC address.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="512"/>
          </list>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SourceMACAddressFilterExclude" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">Note that neither 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} nor 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} support classification based on source MAC address.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="true"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DestMACAddressFilterList" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Classification criterion.
{{list|each representing a MAC Address}}
Each list entry MAY optionally specify a bit-mask, where matching of a packet's MAC address is only to be done for bit positions set to one in the mask.  If no mask is specified, all bits of the MAC Address are to be used for matching.
For example, the list might be: ''01:02:03:04:05:06, 1:22:33:00:00:00/FF:FF:FF:00:00:00, 88:77:66:55:44:33''</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="512"/>
          </list>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DestMACAddressFilterExclude" access="readWrite">
        <description>If {{false}}, on ingress to the interfaces associated with this Filter, the Bridge admits only those packets whose destination MAC Address matches one of the {{param|DestMACAddressFilterList}} entries.  If the {{param|DestMACAddressFilterList}} is empty, no packets are admitted.
If {{true}}, on ingress to the interfaces associated with this Filter, the Bridge admits all packets except those packets whose destination MAC Address matches one of the {{param|DestMACAddressFilterList}} entries.  If the {{param|DestMACAddressFilterList}} is empty, packets are admitted regardless of MAC address.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="true"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Layer2Bridging.Marking.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="MarkingNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="MarkingEnable">
      <description action="replace">Marking table identifying non-default layer 2 marking behavior for packets on egress from the specified interfaces.
This table is not relevant to 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}} Bridges, which are not VLAN-aware.
For 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} Bridges, this table is used for the following:
# It specifies whether VLAN tags are to be removed on egress.
This table also supports several concepts that are not covered by 802.1Q:
# It allows the VLAN ID to be changed on egress.
# It allows the Ethernet Priority to be changed on egress.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="MarkingKey"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="MarkingKey" access="readOnly">
        <description>Unique key for each Marking table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MarkingEnable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this Marking table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MarkingStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">If the Bridge Port table is supported, but none of its entries correspond to {{param|MarkingInterface}}, or if such an entry exists but is disabled, {{param}} MUST NOT indicate {{enum|Enabled}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Enabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MarkingBridgeReference" access="readWrite">
        <description>The ''BridgeKey'' value of the Bridge table entry associated with this Marking table entry.  A value of -1 indicates the Marking table entry is not associated with a Bridge (and has no effect).
The effect of a Marking table entry applies only to packets that have been admitted to the specified bridge (regardless of the ingress interface).</description>
        <syntax>
          <int>
            <range minInclusive="-1"/>
          </int>
          <default type="object" value="-1"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MarkingInterface" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The interface or interfaces associated with this Marking table entry for which the specified marking behavior is to apply on egress from the associated bridge.  The following values are defined.
* To associate this Marking table entry with a single interface listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table, the {{param}} value is set to the value of the corresponding ''AvailableInterfaceKey''.
* ''AllInterfaces'' indicates that this Marking table entry is associated with all LAN and WAN interfaces listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table (all entries of ''InterfaceType'' ''LANInterface'' or ''WANInterface'').  This value is DEPRECATED because of the configuration complexity it requires.
* ''LANInterfaces'' indicates that this Marking table entry is associated with all LAN interfaces listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table (all entries of ''InterfaceType'' ''LANInterface'').  This value is DEPRECATED because of the configuration complexity it requires.
* ''WANInterfaces'' indicates that this Marking table entry is associated with all WAN interfaces listed in the ''AvailableInterface'' table (all entries of ''InterfaceType'' ''WANInterface'').  This value is DEPRECATED because of the configuration complexity it requires.
* {{empty}} indicates the Marking table entry table entry is not associated with any interface (and has no effect)
If there is more than one enabled Marking table entry that specifies one or more of the same interfaces for the same bridge (identical values of {{param|MarkingBridgeReference}}), then for packets on egress from the specified bridge to those interfaces, the applied marking MUST be that specified in the Marking table entry among those in conflict with the lowest {{param|MarkingKey}} value.
If an interface in a given bridge does not have a corresponding Marking table entry, the marking is left unchanged on egress.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="16"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="VLANIDUntag" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">If {{true}}, on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry, all packets are sent Untagged.
If {{false}}, on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry, all packets are sent Tagged with the VLAN ID of the VLAN in which the packet is being bridged.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="VLANIDMark" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} VLAN ID to be used on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry.
A value of -1 indicates that the VLAN ID of the VLAN in which the packet is being bridged is to be used, i.e. no change.
The value of this parameter MUST NOT be 0.
If {{param|VLANIDUntag}} is {{true}}, then no VLAN marking is done since the tag containing the VLAN ID is removed.
Note that 802.1Q does not support re-marking on egress.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int>
            <range minInclusive="-1" maxInclusive="4094"/>
          </int>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetPriorityMark" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Ethernet priority code (as defined in 802.1D {{bibref|802.1D-2004}}) to mark traffic with that falls into this Bridge on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry. A value of -1 indicates no change from the incoming packet or the mark assigned by the classifier.
Note that 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} does not support re-marking on egress.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int>
            <range minInclusive="-1" maxInclusive="7"/>
          </int>
          <default type="object" value="-1"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetPriorityOverride" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">If {{false}}, on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry, the {{param|EthernetPriorityMark}}, if specified, is applied only to packets of priority 0.
If {{true}}, on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry, the {{param|EthernetPriorityMark}}, if specified, is to be applied to all packets on this Bridge.
Note that 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} does not support re-marking on egress.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="VLANIDMarkOverride" access="readWrite">
        <description>If {{false}}, on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry, the {{param|VLANIDMark}}, if specified, is applied only to PriorityOnly packets.
If {{true}}, on egress to the interfaces associated with this Marking table entry, the {{param|VLANIDMark}}, if specified, is to be applied to all packets on this Bridge.
If {{param|VLANIDUntag}} is {{true}}, then no VLAN marking is done since the tag containing the VLAN ID is removed.
Note that 802.1Q {{bibref|802.1Q-2005}} does not support re-marking on egress.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Layer3Forwarding." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object allows the handling of the routing and forwarding configuration of the device.</description>
      <parameter name="DefaultConnectionService" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Specifies the default WAN interface.  The content is the full hierarchical parameter name of the default layer 3 connection object.  Example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.1.WANConnectionDevice.2.WANPPPConnection.1''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ForwardNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of forwarding instances.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Layer3Forwarding.Forwarding.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="ForwardNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description action="replace">Layer 3 forwarding table.
In addition to statically configured routes, this table MUST include dynamic routes learned through layer 3 routing protocols, including RIP, OSPF, DHCP, and IPCP.  The CPE MAY reject attempts to delete or modify a dynamic route entry.
For each incoming packet, the layer 3 forwarding decision is conceptually made as follows:
* Only table entries with a matching {{param|ForwardingPolicy}} are considered, i.e. those that either do not specify a {{param|ForwardingPolicy}}, or else specify a {{param|ForwardingPolicy}} that matches that of the incoming packet. 
* For the remaining table entries, those for which the source address/mask matches are sorted by longest prefix, i.e. with the most specific networks first (an unspecified source address is a wild-card and always matches, with a prefix length of zero). 
* For the remaining table entries, those for which the destination address/mask matches are sorted by longest prefix, i.e. with the most specific networks first (an unspecified destination address is a wild-card and always matches, with a prefix length of zero). 
* The first of the remaining table entries is applied to the packet.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="DestIPAddress"/>
        <parameter ref="DestSubnetMask"/>
        <parameter ref="SourceIPAddress"/>
        <parameter ref="SourceSubnetMask"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the forwarding entry.  On creation, an entry is disabled by default.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Status" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The {{enum|Error}} value MAY be used by the CPE to indicate a locally defined error condition.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Enabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value="Disabled"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Type" access="readWrite" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
This parameter is DEPRECATED because its value could conflict with {{param|DestIPAddress}} and/or {{param|DestSubnetMask}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value="Host"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DestIPAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">A Forwarding table entry for which {{param}} and {{param|DestSubnetMask}} are both {{empty}} or "0.0.0.0" is a default route.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DestSubnetMask" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">If a destination subnet mask is specified, the {{param}} is ANDed with the destination address before comparing with the {{param|DestIPAddress}}.  Otherwise, the full destination address is used as is.
A Forwarding table entry for which {{param|DestIPAddress}} and {{param}} are both {{empty}} or "0.0.0.0" is a default route.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SourceIPAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Source address.  {{empty}} or a value of "0.0.0.0" indicates no source address is specified.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SourceSubnetMask" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">If a source subnet mask is specified, the {{param}} is ANDed with the source address before comparing with the {{param|SourceIPAddress}}.  Otherwise, the full source address is used as is.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="GatewayIPAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">IP address of the gateway.
Only one of GatewayIPAddress and Interface SHOULD be configured for a route.
If both are configured, {{param}} and {{param|Interface}} MUST be consistent with each other.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Interface" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Specifies the egress interface associated with this entry.  {{reference|the layer 3 connection object}}  Example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.1.WANConnectionDevice.2.WANPPPConnection.1''.
Only one of {{param|GatewayIPAddress}} and {{param}} SHOULD be configured for a route.
If both are configured, {{param|GatewayIPAddress}} and {{param}} MUST be consistent with each other.
For a route that was configured by setting {{param|GatewayIPAddress}} but not {{param}}, read access to {{param}} MUST return the full hierarchical parameter name for the route's egress interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <pathRef refType="weak" targetType="row"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ForwardingMetric" access="readWrite">
        <description>Forwarding metric.  A value of -1 indicates this metric is not used.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int/>
          <default type="object" value="-1"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="StaticRoute" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="Status">
        <description>If {{true}}, this route is a Static route.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="true"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.ManagementServer." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains parameters relating to the CPE's association with an ACS.</description>
      <parameter name="URL" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">URL, as defined in {{bibref|RFC3986}}, for the CPE to connect to the ACS using the CPE WAN Management Protocol. 
This parameter MUST be in the form of a valid HTTP or HTTPS URL {{bibref|RFC2616}}.
The ''host'' portion of this URL is used by the CPE for validating the ACS certificate when using SSL or TLS.
Note that on a factory reset of the CPE, the value of this parameter might be reset to its factory value.  If an ACS modifies the value of this parameter, it SHOULD be prepared to accommodate the situation that the original value is restored as the result of a factory reset.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Username" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">Note that on a factory reset of the CPE, the value of this parameter might be reset to its factory value.  If an ACS modifies the value of this parameter, it SHOULD be prepared to accommodate the situation that the original value is restored as the result of a factory reset.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Password" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">Note that on a factory reset of the CPE, the value of this parameter might be reset to its factory value.  If an ACS modifies the value of this parameter, it SHOULD be prepared to accommodate the situation that the original value is restored as the result of a factory reset.</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PeriodicInformEnable" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Whether or not the CPE MUST periodically send CPE information to the ACS using the Inform method call.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PeriodicInformInterval" access="readWrite">
        <description>The duration in seconds of the interval for which the CPE MUST attempt to connect with the ACS and call the Inform method if {{param|PeriodicInformEnable}} is {{true}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PeriodicInformTime" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">An absolute time reference in UTC to determine when the CPE will initiate the periodic Inform method calls.  Each Inform call MUST occur at this reference time plus or minus an integer multiple of the {{param|PeriodicInformInterval}}.
{{param}} is used only to set the "phase" of the periodic Informs.  The actual value of {{param}} can be arbitrarily far into the past or future.
For example, if {{param|PeriodicInformInterval}} is 86400 (a day) and if {{param}} is set to UTC midnight on some day (in the past, present, or future) then periodic Informs will occur every day at UTC midnight.  These MUST begin on the very next midnight, even if {{param}} refers to a day in the future.
The Unknown Time value defined in {{bibref|TR-098a2|section 2.2}} indicates that no particular time reference is specified.  That is, the CPE MAY locally choose the time reference, and needs only to adhere to the specified {{param|PeriodicInformInterval}}.
If absolute time is not available to the CPE, its periodic Inform behavior MUST be the same as if the {{param}} parameter was set to the Unknown Time value.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dateTime/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ParameterKey" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" forcedInform="true">
        <description action="replace">{{param}} provides the ACS a reliable and extensible means to track changes made by the ACS.  The value of {{param}} MUST be equal to the value of the ParameterKey argument from the most recent successful SetParameterValues, AddObject, or DeleteObject method call from the ACS.
The CPE MUST set {{param}} to the value specified in the corresponding method arguments if and only if the method completes successfully and no fault response is generated.  If a method call does not complete successfully (implying that the changes requested in the method did not take effect), the value of {{param}} MUST NOT be modified.
The CPE MUST only modify the value of {{param}} as a result of SetParameterValues, AddObject, DeleteObject, or due to a factory reset.  On factory reset, the value of {{param}} MUST be set to {{empty}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="32"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionRequestURL" access="readOnly" activeNotify="forceDefaultEnabled" forcedInform="true">
        <description action="replace">HTTP URL, as defined in {{bibref|RFC3986}}, for an ACS to make a Connection Request notification to the CPE.
In the form:
http://host:port/path
The ''host'' portion of the URL MAY be the IP address for the management interface of the CPE in lieu of a host name.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionRequestUsername" access="readWrite">
        <description>Username used to authenticate an ACS making a Connection Request to the CPE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionRequestPassword" access="readWrite">
        <description>Password used to authenticate an ACS making a Connection Request to the CPE.</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UpgradesManaged" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Indicates whether or not the ACS will manage upgrades for the CPE.  If {{true}}, the CPE SHOULD NOT use other means other than the ACS to seek out available upgrades.  If {{false}}, the CPE MAY use other means for this purpose.
Note that an autonomous upgrade (reported via an ''10 AUTONOMOUS TRANSFER COMPLETE'' Inform Event code) SHOULD be regarded as a managed upgade if it is performed according to ACS-specified policy.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UDPConnectionRequestAddress" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Address and port to which an ACS MAY send a UDP Connection Request to the CPE (see {{bibref|TR-069a2|Annex G}}).
This parameter is represented in the form of an Authority element as defined in {{bibref|RFC3986}}.  The value MUST be in one of the following two forms:
: host:port
: host
When {{param|STUNEnable}} is {{true}}, the ''host'' and ''port'' portions of this parameter MUST represent the public address and port corresponding to the NAT binding through which the ACS can send UDP Connection Request messages (once this information is learned by the CPE through the use of STUN).
When {{param|STUNEnable}} is {{false}}, the ''host'' and ''port'' portions of the URL MUST represent the local IP address and port on which the CPE is listening for UDP Connection Request messages.
The second form of this parameter MAY be used only if the port value is equal to "80".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UDPConnectionRequestAddressNotificationLimit" access="readWrite">
        <description>The minimum time, in seconds, between Active Notifications resulting from changes to the {{param|UDPConnectionRequestAddress}} (if Active Notification is enabled).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="STUNEnable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the use of STUN by the CPE.  This applies only to the use of STUN in association with the ACS to allow UDP Connection Requests.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="STUNServerAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description>Host name or IP address of the STUN server for the CPE to send Binding Requests if STUN is enabled via {{param|STUNEnable}}.
If {{empty}} and {{param|STUNEnable}} is {{true}}, the CPE MUST use the address of the ACS extracted from the host portion of the ACS URL.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="STUNServerPort" access="readWrite">
        <description>Port number of the STUN server for the CPE to send Binding Requests if STUN is enabled via {{param|STUNEnable}}.
By default, this SHOULD be the equal to the default STUN port, 3478.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="0" maxInclusive="65535"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="STUNUsername" access="readWrite">
        <description>If not {{empty}}, the value of the STUN USERNAME attribute to be used in Binding Requests (only if message integrity has been requested by the STUN server).
If {{empty}}, the CPE MUST NOT send STUN Binding Requests with message integrity.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="STUNPassword" access="readWrite">
        <description>The value of the STUN Password to be used in computing the MESSAGE-INTEGRITY attribute to be used in Binding Requests (only if message integrity has been requested by the STUN server).</description>
        <syntax hidden="true">
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="STUNMaximumKeepAlivePeriod" access="readWrite">
        <description>If STUN Is enabled, the maximum period, in seconds, that STUN Binding Requests MUST be sent by the CPE for the purpose of maintaining the binding in the Gateway.  This applies specifically to Binding Requests sent from the UDP Connection Request address and port.
A value of -1 indicates that no maximum period is specified.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int>
            <range minInclusive="-1"/>
          </int>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="STUNMinimumKeepAlivePeriod" access="readWrite">
        <description>If STUN Is enabled, the minimum period, in seconds, that STUN Binding Requests can be sent by the CPE for the purpose of maintaining the binding in the Gateway.  This limit applies only to Binding Requests sent from the UDP Connection Request address and port, and only those that do not contain the BINDING-CHANGE attribute.  This limit does not apply to retransmissions following the procedures defined in {{bibref|RFC3489}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="NATDetected" access="readOnly">
        <description>When STUN is enabled, this parameter indicates whether or not the CPE has detected address and/or port mapping in use.
A {{true}} value indicates that the received MAPPED-ADDRESS in the most recent Binding Response differs from the CPE's source address and port.
When STUNEnable is {{false}}, this value MUST be {{false}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ManageableDeviceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of entries in the {{object|ManageableDevice}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.ManagementServer.ManageableDevice.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="ManageableDeviceNumberOfEntries">
      <description action="replace">Each entry in this table corresponds to a distinct LAN Device that supports Device-Gateway Association according to {{bibref|TR-069a2|Annex F}} as indicated by the presence of the DHCP option specified in that Annex.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="ManufacturerOUI"/>
        <parameter ref="SerialNumber"/>
        <parameter ref="ProductClass"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="ManufacturerOUI" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Organizationally unique identifier of the Device manufacturer as provided to the Gateway by the Device.  Represented as a six hexadecimal-digit value using all upper-case letters and including any leading zeros.  The value MUST be a valid OUI as defined in {{bibref|OUI}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="6"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SerialNumber" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Serial number of the Device as provided to the Gateway by the Device.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ProductClass" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Identifier of the class of product for which the Device's serial number applies as provided to the Gateway by the Device.
If the Device does not provide a Product Class, then this parameter MUST be {{empty}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Host" access="readOnly">
        <description>{{reference|a ''Host'' table row}}  This list MUST include an item for each ''Host'' table entry, whether active or inactive, that corresponds to this physical LAN Device.
As such entries are added to or removed from the ''Host'' tables, the value of this parameter MUST be updated accordingly.
For example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.1,InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.5''</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="1024"/>
          </list>
          <string>
            <pathRef refType="strong" targetType="row" targetParent="InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.Hosts.Host."/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.Time." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">This object contains parameters relating an NTP or SNTP time client in the CPE.</description>
      <parameter name="NTPServer1" access="readWrite">
        <description>First NTP timeserver.  Either a host name or IP address.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="NTPServer2" access="readWrite">
        <description>Second NTP timeserver.  Either a host name or IP address.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="CurrentLocalTime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The current date and time in the CPE's local time zone.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dateTime/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LocalTimeZone" access="readWrite" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="replace">The local time zone offset from UTC, ignoring daylight savings time adjustments, in the form:
: +hh:mm
: -hh:mm
For example, this will always be "-08:00" for California, "+00:00" or "-00:00" for the United Kingdom, and "+01:00" for France.
This parameter is OBSOLETED because the information that it represents is fully covered by {{param|LocalTimeZoneName}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="6"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LocalTimeZoneName" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">The name SHOULD be encoded according to IEEE 1003.1 (POSIX).  The following is an example value: ''EST+5EDT,M4.1.0/2,M10.5.0/2''</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DaylightSavingsUsed" access="readWrite" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="append">This parameter is OBSOLETED because the information that it represents is fully covered by {{param|LocalTimeZoneName}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DaylightSavingsStart" access="readWrite" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="replace">Current local date and time at which the switch to daylight savings time occurs.  If daylight savings time is not used, this value is ignored.
This parameter is OBSOLETED because the information that it represents is fully covered by {{param|LocalTimeZoneName}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dateTime/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DaylightSavingsEnd" access="readWrite" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="replace">Current local date and time at which the switch from daylight savings time will occur.  If daylight savings time is not used, this value is ignored.
This parameter is OBSOLETED because the information that it represents is fully covered by {{param|LocalTimeZoneName}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dateTime/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite" dmr:previousParameter="">
        <description>Enables or disables the NTP or SNTP time client.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Status" access="readOnly">
        <description>Status of Time support on the CPE.  {{enum}}
The {{enum|Unsynchronized}} value indicates that the CPE's absolute time has not yet been set.
The {{enum|Synchronized}} value indicates that the CPE has acquired accurate absolute time; its current time is accurate.
The {{enum|Error_FailedToSynchronize}} value indicates that the CPE failed to acquire accurate absolute time; its current time is not accurate.
The {{enum|Error}} value MAY be used by the CPE to indicate a locally defined error condition.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
            <enumeration value="Unsynchronized"/>
            <enumeration value="Synchronized"/>
            <enumeration value="Error_FailedToSynchronize"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.TraceRouteDiagnostics." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object is defines access to an IP-layer trace-route test for the specified IP interface.</description>
      <parameter name="DiagnosticsState" access="readWrite" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Indicates availability of diagnostic data.  {{enum}}
If the ACS sets the value of this parameter to {{enum|Requested}}, the CPE MUST initiate the corresponding diagnostic test.  When writing, the only allowed value is {{enum|Requested}}.  To ensure the use of the proper test parameters (the writable parameters in this object), the test parameters MUST be set either prior to or at the same time as (in the same SetParameterValues) setting the {{param}} to {{enum|Requested}}.
When requested, the CPE SHOULD wait until after completion of the communication session with the ACS before starting the diagnostic.
When the diagnostic initiated by the ACS is completed (successfully or not), the CPE MUST establish a new connection to the ACS to allow the ACS to view the results, indicating the Event code ''8 DIAGNOSTICS COMPLETE'' in the Inform message.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="None" access="readOnly"/>
            <enumeration value="Requested"/>
            <enumeration value="Complete" access="readOnly"/>
            <enumeration value="Error_CannotResolveHostName" access="readOnly"/>
            <enumeration value="Error_MaxHopCountExceeded" access="readOnly"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Interface" access="readWrite">
        <description>{{reference|the WAN or LAN IP-layer interface over which the test is to be performed}}  This identifies the source IP address to use when performing the test.
The following is a WAN interface example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.1.WANConnectionDevice.2.WANPPPConnection.1''
The following is a LAN interface example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.LANHostConfigManagement.IPInterface.1''</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
            <pathRef refType="weak" targetType="row"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Host" access="readWrite">
        <description>Host name or address of the host to find a route to</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="NumberOfTries" access="readWrite">
        <description>Number of tries per hop. Set prior to running Diagnostic.  By default, the CPE SHOULD set this value to 3.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="3"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Timeout" access="readWrite">
        <description>Timeout in milliseconds for the trace route test.  By default the CPE SHOULD set this value to 5000.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DataBlockSize" access="readWrite">
        <description>Size of the data block in bytes to be sent for each trace route.  By default, the CPE SHOULD set this value to 38.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="65535"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DSCP" access="readWrite">
        <description>DiffServ codepoint to be used for the test packets.  By default the CPE SHOULD set this value to 0.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="0" maxInclusive="63"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxHopCount" access="readWrite">
        <description>The maximum number of hop used in outgoing probe packets (max TTL).  By default the CPE SHOULD set this value to 30.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="64"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ResponseTime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Result parameter indicating the response time in milliseconds the most recent trace route test.  If a route could not be determined, this value MUST be zero.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RouteHopsNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Number of entries in the {{object|RouteHops}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.TraceRouteDiagnostics.RouteHops.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="RouteHopsNumberOfEntries">
      <description>Contains the array of results returned.  If a route could not be determined, this array will be empty</description>
      <parameter name="HopHost" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Result parameter indicating the Host Name if DNS is able to resolve or IP Address of a hop along the discovered route.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="HopHostAddress" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>If this parameter is not {{empty}} it will contain the last IP address of the host returned for this hop and the {{param|HopHost}} will contain the Host Name returned from the reverse DNS query.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="HopErrorCode" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Contains the error code returned for this hop  This code is directly from the ICMP CODE field.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="HopRTTimes" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Contains one or more round trip times in milliseconds (one for each repetition) for this hop.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="16"/>
          </list>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="WANDeviceNumberOfEntries">
      <description>Each instance contains all objects associated with a particular physical WAN interface.</description>
      <parameter name="WANConnectionNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|WANConnectionDevice}} in this ''WANDevice''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANCommonInterfaceConfig." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object models WAN interface properties common across all connection instances.</description>
      <parameter name="EnabledForInternet" access="readWrite">
        <description>Used to enable or disable access to and from the Internet across all connection instances.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WANAccessType" access="readOnly">
        <description>Specifies the WAN access (modem) type.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="DSL"/>
            <enumeration value="Ethernet"/>
            <enumeration value="POTS"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Layer1UpstreamMaxBitRate" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Specifies the maximum upstream theoretical bit rate for the WAN device in bits per second.  This describes the maximum possible rate given the type of interface assuming the best-case operating environment, regardless of the current operating rate.
For example, if the physical interface is 100BaseT, this value would be 100000000, regardless of the current operating rate.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Layer1DownstreamMaxBitRate" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Specifies the maximum downstream theoretical bit rate for the WAN device in bits per second.  This describes the maximum possible rate given the type of interface assuming the best-case operating environment, regardless of the current operating rate.
For example, if the physical interface is 100BaseT, this value would be 100000000, regardless of the current operating rate.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PhysicalLinkStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description>Indicates the state of the physical connection (link) from WANDevice to a connected entity.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Up"/>
            <enumeration value="Down"/>
            <enumeration value="Initializing"/>
            <enumeration value="Unavailable"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalBytesSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The cumulative counter for total number of bytes sent upstream across all connection service instances on the WAN device.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalBytesReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The cumulative counter for total number of bytes received downstream across all connection service instances on the WAN device.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The cumulative counter for total number of packets (IP or PPP) sent upstream across all connection service instances on the WAN device.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The cumulative counter for total number of packets (IP or PPP) received downstream across all connection service instances on the WAN device.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="WANConnectionNumberOfEntries">
      <description action="replace">Each instance contains objects associated with a given WAN link.  In the case of DSL, each instance corresponds to either a single ATM VC or a PTM Ethernet link.  On creation of a ''WANConnectionDevice'' instance, there are initially no connection objects contained within.  In the case of Ethernet (interface or link), only one ''WANConnectionDevice'' instance is supported.</description>
      <parameter name="WANIPConnectionNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|WANIPConnection}} in this ''WANConnectionDevice''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WANPPPConnectionNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Number of instances of {{object|WANPPPConnection}} in this ''WANConnectionDevice''.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANDSLLinkConfig." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">This object models the ATM layer properties specific to a single physical connection of a DSL modem used for Internet access on a CPE.  This object is intended for a CPE with a DSL modem WAN interface, and is exclusive of any other ''WAN*LinkConfig'' object within a given ''WANConnectionDevice'' instance.</description>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the link.  On creation of a ''WANConnectionDevice'', this object is disabled by default.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LinkStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description>Status of the link.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Up"/>
            <enumeration value="Down"/>
            <enumeration value="Initializing"/>
            <enumeration value="Unavailable"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LinkType" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Indicates the type of DSL connection and refers to the complete stack of protocol used for this connection.  {{enum}}
The value {{enum|PPPoE}} has always been DEPRECATED and {{enum|EoA}} SHOULD be used instead (see {{bibref|TR-098a2|Annex B}}).  The ACS MUST NOT set this parameter to {{enum|PPPoE}} and the CPE MUST reject attempts to do so.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="EoA">
              <description action="replace">RFC 2684 {{bibref|RFC2684}} bridged Ethernet over ATM</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="IPoA">
              <description action="replace">RFC 2684 {{bibref|RFC2684}} routed IP over ATM</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="PPPoA">
              <description action="replace">RFC 2364 {{bibref|RFC2634}} PPP over ATM</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="PPPoE" status="deprecated">
              <description action="replace">RFC 2516 {{bibref|RFC2516}} PPP over Ethernet on RFC 2684 {{bibref|RFC2684}} bridged Ethernet over ATM</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="CIP">
              <description action="replace">RFC 2225 {{bibref|RFC2225}} Classical IP over ATM</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="Unconfigured"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AutoConfig" access="readOnly">
        <description action="replace">Indicates if the CPE is currently using some auto configuration mechanisms for this connection.  If this variable is {{true}}, all writable variables in this connection instance become read-only. Any attempt to change one of these variables SHOULD fail and an error SHOULD be returned.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DestinationAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">The "PVC:" or "SVC:" prefix is part of the parameter value and MUST be followed by 0 or 1 space characters.  For example, possible values for this parameter are "PVC:8/23" or "PVC: 0/35".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATMTransmittedBlocks" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The current count of successfully transmitted cells.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATMReceivedBlocks" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The current count of successfully received cells.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AAL5CRCErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it overlaps with the {{param|ATMCRCErrors}} parameter. If present, it MUST have the same value as the {{param|ATMCRCErrors}} parameter if AAL5 is in use, or 0 if AAL5 is not in use.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATMCRCErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">Count of the ATM layer cyclic redundancy check (CRC) errors.
This refers to CRC errors at the ATM adaptation layer (AAL). The AAL in use is indicated by the {{param|ATMAAL}} parameter. The value of the {{param}} parameter MUST be 0 for AAL types that have no CRCs.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANEthernetLinkConfig." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">This object models the Ethernet link layer properties specific to a single physical connection used for Internet access on a CPE.  This object is intended for a CPE with an Ethernet WAN interface, and is exclusive of any other ''WAN*LinkConfig'' object within a given ''WANConnectionDevice'' instance.  Note that this object is not related to the Ethernet protocol layer sometimes used in associated with a DSL connection.</description>
      <parameter name="EthernetLinkStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description>Status of the Ethernet link.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Up"/>
            <enumeration value="Down"/>
            <enumeration value="Unavailable"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANIPConnection.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="WANIPConnectionNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description action="append">If the ''Layer2Bridging'' object is implemented, the view that it provides of the CPE's underlying bridging configuration MUST be consistent with the view provided by any ''LANDevice'' and ''WAN**Connection'' objects.  The implications of this are explained in {{bibref|TR-098a2|Annex A.6}}.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="ExternalIPAddress"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the connection instance.  On creation of a ''WANIPConnection'' instance, it is initially disabled.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The value {{enum|Disconneting}} is DEPRECATED because it is a typo.  The ACS MUST treat {{enum|Disconneting}} and {{enum|Disconnecting}} the same.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Unconfigured"/>
            <enumeration value="Connecting"/>
            <enumeration value="Connected"/>
            <enumeration value="PendingDisconnect"/>
            <enumeration value="Disconneting" status="deprecated"/>
            <enumeration value="Disconnecting"/>
            <enumeration value="Disconnected"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PossibleConnectionTypes" access="readOnly">
        <description>Types of connections possible for this connection instance.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list/>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Unconfigured"/>
            <enumeration value="IP_Routed"/>
            <enumeration value="IP_Bridged"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionType" access="readWrite">
        <description>Specifies the connection type of the connection instance.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Unconfigured"/>
            <enumeration value="IP_Routed"/>
            <enumeration value="IP_Bridged"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Name" access="readWrite">
        <description>User-readable name of this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Uptime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The time in seconds that this connection has been up.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LastConnectionError" access="readOnly">
        <description>The cause of failure for the last connection setup attempt.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value="ERROR_NONE"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RSIPAvailable" access="readOnly">
        <description>Indicates if Realm-specific IP (RSIP) is available as a feature on the CPE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="NATEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Indicates if Network Address Translation (NAT) is enabled for this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="AddressingType" access="readWrite">
        <description>The method used to assign an address to the WAN side interface of the CPE for this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="DHCP"/>
            <enumeration value="Static"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ExternalIPAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description>This is the external IP address used by NAT for this connection.  This parameter is configurable only if the {{param|AddressingType}} is {{enum|Static|AddressingType}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SubnetMask" access="readWrite">
        <description>Subnet mask of the WAN interface.  This parameter is configurable only if the {{param|AddressingType}} is {{enum|Static|AddressingType}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DefaultGateway" access="readWrite">
        <description>The IP address of the default gateway for this connection.  This parameter is configurable only if the {{param|AddressingType}} is {{enum|Static|AddressingType}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DNSEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Whether or not the device SHOULD attempt to query a DNS server across this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="true"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DNSOverrideAllowed" access="readWrite">
        <description>Whether or not a manually set, non-empty DNS address can be overridden by a DNS entry received from the WAN.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DNSServers" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">DNS server IP addresses for this connection.  Support for more than three DNS Servers is OPTIONAL.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </list>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description>The physical address of the ''WANIPConnection'' if applicable.  Configurable only if {{param|MACAddressOverride}} is present and {{true}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="MACAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionTrigger" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The above values are defined as follows:
* {{enum|OnDemand}}: If this IP connection is disconnected for any reason, it is to remain disconnected until the CPE has one or more packets to communicate over this connection, at which time the CPE automatically attempts to reestablish the connection.
* {{enum|AlwaysOn}}: If this IP connection is disconnected for any reason, the CPE automatically attempts to reestablish the connection (and continues to attempt to reestablish the connection as long it remains disconnected).
* {{enum|Manual}}: If this IP connection is disconnected for any reason, it is to remain disconnected until the user of the CPE explicitly instructs the CPE to reestablish the connection.
Note that the reason for an IP connection becoming disconnected to begin with might be either external to the CPE, such as non-renewal of a DHCP lease or momentary disconnection of the physical interface, or internal to the CPE, such as use of the {{param|IdleDisconnectTime}} and/or {{param|AutoDisconnectTime}} parameters in this object.
Note also that the means by which a CPE would keep an IP connection disconnected (while waiting for the designated trigger) if it is otherwise physically connected and has an IP address is a local matter specific to the implementation of the CPE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value="OnDemand"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RouteProtocolRx" access="readWrite">
        <description>Defines the Rx protocol to be used.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Off"/>
            <enumeration value="RIPv1" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="RIPv2" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="OSPF" optional="true"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value="Off"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Total number of port mapping entries.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Reset" access="readWrite" dmr:previousParameter="Enable">
        <description>When set to {{true}}, the device MUST tear down the existing IP connection represented by this object and establish a new one.  
The device MUST initiate the reset after completion of the current CWMP session.  The device MAY delay resetting the connection in order to avoid interruption of a user service such as an ongoing voice call.
When read, this parameter always returns {{false}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANIPConnection.{i}.DHCPClient." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1" dmr:previousObject="">
      <description>This object contains DHCP client configuration parameters.</description>
      <parameter name="SentDHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>The number of entries in the {{object|SentDHCPOption}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ReqDHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>The number of entries in the {{object|ReqDHCPOption}} table.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANIPConnection.{i}.DHCPClient.ReqDHCPOption.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="ReqDHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description>Each instance of this object represents a DHCP option that MUST, if enabled, be requested in DHCP client requests. All requested DHCP options MUST be listed.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="Tag"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this ReqDHCPOption table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Tag" access="readWrite">
        <description>Option tag as defined in RFC 2132 {{bibref|RFC2132}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="254"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Value" access="readOnly">
        <description>Base64 encoded most recently received DHCP option value.
If no option value has been received, then the value MUST represent {{empty}}.
Received DHCP option values MAY, but need not, persist across CPE reboots.</description>
        <syntax>
          <base64>
            <size minLength="0" maxLength="255"/>
          </base64>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANIPConnection.{i}.DHCPClient.SentDHCPOption.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="SentDHCPOptionNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description>Each instance of this object represents a DHCP option that MUST, if enabled, be sent in DHCP client requests.  All sent DHCP options MUST be listed.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="Tag"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this SentDHCPOption table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Tag" access="readWrite">
        <description>Option tag as defined in RFC 2132 {{bibref|RFC2132}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1" maxInclusive="254"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Value" access="readWrite">
        <description>Base64 encoded option value.</description>
        <syntax>
          <base64>
            <size minLength="0" maxLength="255"/>
          </base64>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANIPConnection.{i}.PortMapping.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="PortMappingNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="PortMappingEnabled">
      <description action="replace">Port mapping table.
This table MUST contain all NAT port mappings associated with this connection, including static and dynamic port mappings programmatically created via local control protocol, such as UPnP.
This table MUST NOT contain dynamic NAT binding entries associated with the normal operation of NAT.
At most one entry in an instance of this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param|RemoteHost}}, {{param|ExternalPort}}, and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}.  If the ACS attempts to set the parameters of an existing entry such that this requirement would be violated, the CPE MUST reject the request.  In this case, the SetParameterValues response MUST include a SetParameterValuesFault element for each parameter in the corresponding request whose modification would have resulted in such a violation.  On creation of a new table entry, the CPE MUST choose default values for {{param|ExternalPort}} and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}} such that the new entry does not conflict with any existing entry.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="RemoteHost"/>
        <parameter ref="ExternalPort"/>
        <parameter ref="PortMappingProtocol"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="PortMappingEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the port mapping instance.  On creation, an entry is disabled by default.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingLeaseDuration" access="readWrite" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">Determines the time to live, in seconds, of a port-mapping lease, where "time to live" means the number of seconds before the port mapping expires. 
A value of 0 means the port mapping is static. Support for dynamic (non-static) port mappings is OPTIONAL.  That is, the only value for {{param}} that MUST be supported is 0.
For a dynamic (non-static) port mapping, when this parameter is read, the value represents the time remaining on the port-mapping lease.  That is, for a dynamic port mapping, the value counts down toward 0.  When a dynamic port-mapping lease expires, the CPE MUST automatically terminate that port mapping, and MUST automatically delete the corresponding ''PortMapping'' table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RemoteHost" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">This parameter is the IP address of the source of inbound packets.  {{empty}} indicates a "wildcard" (this will be a wildcard in most cases).  CPE are REQUIRED only to support wildcards.
When {{param}} is a wildcard, all traffic sent to the {{param|ExternalPort}} on the WAN interface of the gateway is forwarded to the {{param|InternalClient}} on the {{param|InternalPort}}.
When {{param}} is specified as one external IP address, the NAT will only forward inbound packets from this {{param}} to the {{param|InternalClient}}, all other packets will be dropped. 
If a CPE supports non-wildcard values for {{param}}, it MAY additionally support the ability to have more than one port mapping with the same {{param|ExternalPort}} and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}, but with differing values of {{param}}.
When wildcard values are used for {{param}} and/or {{param|ExternalPort}}, the following precedence order applies (with the highest precedence listed first):
# Explicit {{param}}, explicit {{param|ExternalPort}}
# Explicit {{param}}, wildcard {{param|ExternalPort}}
# Wildcard {{param}}, explicit {{param|ExternalPort}}
# Wildcard {{param}}, wildcard {{param|ExternalPort}}
If an incoming packet matches the criteria associated with more than one entry in this table, the CPE MUST apply the port mapping associated with the highest precedence entry.
At most one entry in this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param}}, {{param|ExternalPort}}, and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ExternalPort" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The external port (or the first port of a range of external ports) that the NAT gateway would listen on for connection requests to a corresponding {{param|InternalPort}}. Inbound packets to this external port on the WAN interface SHOULD be forwarded to {{param|InternalClient}} on the {{param|InternalPort}}.
A value of zero (0) represents a "wildcard".  If this value is a wildcard, connection requests on all external ports (that are not otherwise mapped) will be forwarded to {{param|InternalClient}}.  In the wildcard case, the value(s) of {{param|InternalPort}} on {{param|InternalClient}} are ignored.
When wildcard values are used for {{param|RemoteHost}} and/or {{param}}, the following precedence order applies (with the highest precedence listed first):
# Explicit {{param|RemoteHost}}, explicit {{param}}
# Explicit {{param|RemoteHost}}, wildcard {{param}}
# Wildcard {{param|RemoteHost}}, explicit {{param}}
# Wildcard {{param|RemoteHost}}, wildcard {{param}}
If an incoming packet matches the criteria associated with more than one entry in this table, the CPE MUST apply the port mapping associated with the highest precedence entry.
At most one entry in this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param|RemoteHost}}, {{param}}, and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InternalPort" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The port on {{param|InternalClient}} that the gateway SHOULD forward connection requests to.  A value of zero (0) is not allowed.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingProtocol" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
At most one entry in this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param|RemoteHost}}, {{param|ExternalPort}}, and {{param}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="TCP"/>
            <enumeration value="UDP"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InternalClient" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The IP address or DNS host name of an internal client (on the LAN).
Support for an IP address is mandatory.  If {{param}} is specified as an IP address and the LAN device's IP address subsequently changes, the port mapping MUST remain associated with the original IP address.
Support for DNS host names is OPTIONAL.  If {{param}} is specified as a DNS host name and the LAN device's IP address subsequently changes, the port mapping MUST remain associated with this LAN device.  In this case, it is the responsibility of the CPE to maintain the name-to-address mapping in the event of IP address changes.  This can be accomplished, for example, by assigning the DNS host name via use of DHCP option 12 (Host Name) or option 81 (FQDN).  Note that the ACS can learn the host name associated with a given LAN device via the ''Hosts'' table ({{object|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.Hosts}}).
Read access to this parameter MUST always return the exact value that was last set by the ACS.  For example, if the internal client is set to a DNS host name, it MUST read back as a DNS host name and not as an IP address.
{{empty}} indicates an unconfigured {{param}}. If this parameter is unconfigured, this port mapping MUST NOT be operational.
It MUST be possible to set the {{param}} to the broadcast IP address 255.255.255.255 for UDP mappings. This is to enable multiple NAT clients to use the same well-known port simultaneously.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingDescription" access="readWrite">
        <description>User-readable description of this port mapping.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANIPConnection.{i}.Stats." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">This object contains statistics for all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.  The contents of this object SHOULD be identical for each such connection.
This object is intended only for ''WANConnectionDevice''s that can support an Ethernet-layer on this interface (e.g., ''PPPoE'', ''IPoE'').</description>
      <parameter name="EthernetBytesSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes transmitted, including framing characters, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetBytesReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes received, including framing characters, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets transmitted over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets which were received over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetErrorsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets that could not be transmitted because of errors, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetErrorsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets that contained errors preventing them from being deliverable, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetUnicastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address, including those that were discarded or not sent, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetUnicastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetDiscardPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being transmitted, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetDiscardPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being deliverable, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetMulticastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission, including those that were discarded or not sent, which were addressed to a multicast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetMulticastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a multicast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetBroadcastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission, including those that were discarded or not sent, which were addressed to a broadcast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetBroadcastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a broadcast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetUnknownProtoPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets which were discarded because of an unknown or unsupported protocol, received over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANPPPConnection.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="WANPPPConnectionNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="Enable">
      <description action="append">If the ''Layer2Bridging'' object is implemented, the view that it provides of the CPE's underlying bridging configuration MUST be consistent with the view provided by any ''LANDevice'' and ''WAN**Connection'' objects.  The implications of this are explained in {{bibref|TR-098a2|Annex A.6}}.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="ExternalIPAddress"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the connection instance.  On creation of a ''WANPPPConnection'' instance, it is initially disabled.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionStatus" access="readOnly">
        <description>Current status of the connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Unconfigured"/>
            <enumeration value="Connecting"/>
            <enumeration value="Authenticating"/>
            <enumeration value="Connected"/>
            <enumeration value="PendingDisconnect"/>
            <enumeration value="Disconnecting"/>
            <enumeration value="Disconnected"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PossibleConnectionTypes" access="readOnly">
        <description>Types of connections possible for this connection instance.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list/>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Unconfigured"/>
            <enumeration value="IP_Routed"/>
            <enumeration value="DHCP_Spoofed"/>
            <enumeration value="PPPoE_Bridged"/>
            <enumeration value="PPPoE_Relay"/>
            <enumeration value="PPTP_Relay"/>
            <enumeration value="L2TP_Relay"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionType" access="readWrite">
        <description>Specifies the connection type of the connection instance.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Unconfigured"/>
            <enumeration value="IP_Routed"/>
            <enumeration value="DHCP_Spoofed"/>
            <enumeration value="PPPoE_Bridged"/>
            <enumeration value="PPPoE_Relay"/>
            <enumeration value="PPTP_Relay"/>
            <enumeration value="L2TP_Relay"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Name" access="readWrite">
        <description>User-readable name of this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Uptime" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The time in seconds that this connection has been up.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LastConnectionError" access="readOnly">
        <description>The cause of failure for the last connection setup attempt.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value="ERROR_NONE"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RSIPAvailable" access="readOnly">
        <description>Indicates if Realm-specific IP (RSIP) is available as a feature on the CPE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="NATEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Indicates if Network Address Translation (NAT) is enabled for this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Username" access="readWrite">
        <description>Username to be used for authentication.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Password" access="readWrite">
        <description>Password to be usef for authentication.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ExternalIPAddress" access="readOnly">
        <description>This is the external IP address used by NAT for this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DNSEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Whether or not the device SHOULD attempt to query a DNS server across this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="true"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DNSOverrideAllowed" access="readWrite">
        <description>Whether or not a manually set, non-empty DNS address can be overridden by a DNS entry received from the WAN.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DNSServers" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">DNS server IP addresses for this connection.  Support for more than three DNS Servers is OPTIONAL.</description>
        <syntax>
          <list>
            <size maxLength="64"/>
          </list>
          <dataType ref="IPAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddress" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">If {{param|TransportType}} is {{enum|PPPoA|TransportType}}, the value of this parameter is irrelevant and MUST be {{empty}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="MACAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TransportType" access="readOnly">
        <description>PPP transport type of the connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="PPPoA"/>
            <enumeration value="PPPoE"/>
            <enumeration value="L2TP">
              <description>for future use</description>
            </enumeration>
            <enumeration value="PPTP">
              <description>for future use</description>
            </enumeration>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PPPoEACName" access="readWrite">
        <description>PPPoE Access Concentrator.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PPPoEServiceName" access="readWrite">
        <description>PPPoE Service Name.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionTrigger" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">Trigger used to establish the PPP connection.  {{enum}}
The above values are defined as follows:
* {{enum|OnDemand}}: If this PPP connection is disconnected for any reason, it is to remain disconnected until the CPE has one or more packets to communicate over this connection, at which time the CPE automatically attempts to reestablish the connection.
* {{enum|AlwaysOn}}: If this PPP connection is disconnected for any reason, the CPE automatically attempts to reestablish the connection (and continues to attempt to reestablish the connection as long it remains disconnected).
* {{enum|Manual}}: If this PPP connection is disconnected for any reason, it is to remain disconnected until the user of the CPE explicitly instructs the CPE to reestablish the connection.
Note that the reason for a PPP connection becoming disconnected to begin with might be either external to the CPE, such as termination by the BRAS or momentary disconnection of the physical interface, or internal to the CPE, such as use of the {{param|IdleDisconnectTime}} and/or {{param|AutoDisconnectTime}} parameters in this object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value="OnDemand"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RouteProtocolRx" access="readWrite">
        <description>Defines the Rx protocol to be used.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Off"/>
            <enumeration value="RIPv1" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="RIPv2" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="OSPF" optional="true"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value="Off"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly">
        <description>Total number of port mapping entries.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Reset" access="readWrite" dmr:previousParameter="Enable">
        <description>When set to {{true}}, the device MUST tear down the existing PPP connection represented by this object and establish a new one.  
The device MUST initiate the reset after completion of the current CWMP session.  The device MAY delay resetting the connection in order to avoid interruption of a user service such as an ongoing voice call.  
When read, this parameter always returns {{false}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PPPoESessionID" access="readOnly" dmr:previousParameter="ConnectionType">
        <description>Represents the PPPoE Session ID.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt>
            <range minInclusive="1"/>
          </unsignedInt>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DefaultGateway" access="readOnly">
        <description>Represents the IP Address of the remote end Default Gateway established through PPPoE.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANPPPConnection.{i}.PortMapping.{i}." access="readWrite" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="PortMappingNumberOfEntries" enableParameter="PortMappingEnabled">
      <description action="replace">Port mapping table.
This table MUST contain all NAT port mappings associated with this connection, including static and dynamic port mappings programmatically created via local control protocol, such as UPnP.
This table MUST NOT contain dynamic NAT binding entries associated with the normal operation of NAT.
At most one entry in an instance of this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param|RemoteHost}}, {{param|ExternalPort}}, and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}.  If the ACS attempts to set the parameters of an existing entry such that this requirement would be violated, the CPE MUST reject the request.  In this case, the SetParameterValues response MUST include a SetParameterValuesFault element for each parameter in the corresponding request whose modification would have resulted in such a violation.  On creation of a new table entry, the CPE MUST choose default values for {{param|ExternalPort}} and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}} such that the new entry does not conflict with any existing entry.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="RemoteHost"/>
        <parameter ref="ExternalPort"/>
        <parameter ref="PortMappingProtocol"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="PortMappingEnabled" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the port mapping instance.  On creation, an entry is disabled by default.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
          <default type="object" value="false"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingLeaseDuration" access="readWrite" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">Determines the time to live, in seconds, of a port-mapping lease, where "time to live" means the number of seconds before the port mapping expires. 
A value of 0 means the port mapping is static. Support for dynamic (non-static) port mappings is OPTIONAL.  That is, the only value for {{param}} that MUST be supported is 0.
For a dynamic (non-static) port mapping, when this parameter is read, the value represents the time remaining on the port-mapping lease.  That is, for a dynamic port mapping, the value counts down toward 0.  When a dynamic port-mapping lease expires, the CPE MUST automatically terminate that port mapping, and MUST automatically delete the corresponding ''PortMapping'' table entry.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="RemoteHost" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">This parameter is the IP address of the source of inbound packets.  {{empty}} indicates a "wildcard" (this will be a wildcard in most cases).  CPE are REQUIRED only to support wildcards.
When {{param}} is a wildcard, all traffic sent to the {{param|ExternalPort}} on the WAN interface of the gateway is forwarded to the {{param|InternalClient}} on the {{param|InternalPort}}.
When {{param}} is specified as one external IP address, the NAT will only forward inbound packets from this {{param}} to the {{param|InternalClient}}, all other packets will be dropped. 
If a CPE supports non-wildcard values for {{param}}, it MAY additionally support the ability to have more than one port mapping with the same {{param|ExternalPort}} and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}, but with differing values of {{param}}.
When wildcard values are used for {{param}} and/or {{param|ExternalPort}}, the following precedence order applies (with the highest precedence listed first):
# Explicit {{param}}, explicit {{param|ExternalPort}}
# Explicit {{param}}, wildcard {{param|ExternalPort}}
# Wildcard {{param}}, explicit {{param|ExternalPort}}
# Wildcard {{param}}, wildcard {{param|ExternalPort}}
If an incoming packet matches the criteria associated with more than one entry in this table, the CPE MUST apply the port mapping associated with the highest precedence entry.
At most one entry in this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param}}, {{param|ExternalPort}}, and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ExternalPort" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The external port (or the first port of a range of external ports) that the NAT gateway would listen on for connection requests to a corresponding {{param|InternalPort}}. Inbound packets to this external port on the WAN interface SHOULD be forwarded to {{param|InternalClient}} on the {{param|InternalPort}}.
A value of zero (0) represents a "wildcard".  If this value is a wildcard, connection request on all external ports (that are not otherwise mapped) will be forwarded to {{param|InternalClient}}.  In the wildcard case, the value(s) of {{param|InternalPort}} on {{param|InternalClient}} are ignored.
When wildcard values are used for {{param|RemoteHost}} and/or {{param}}, the following precedence order applies (with the highest precedence listed first):
# Explicit {{param|RemoteHost}}, explicit {{param}}
# Explicit {{param|RemoteHost}}, wildcard {{param}}
# Wildcard {{param|RemoteHost}}, explicit {{param}}
# Wildcard {{param|RemoteHost}}, wildcard {{param}}
If an incoming packet matches the criteria associated with more than one entry in this table, the CPE MUST apply the port mapping associated with the highest precedence entry.
At most one entry in this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param|RemoteHost}}, {{param}}, and {{param|PortMappingProtocol}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InternalPort" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The port on {{param|InternalClient}} that the gateway SHOULD forward connection requests to.  A value of zero (0) is not allowed.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingProtocol" access="readWrite">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
At most one entry in this table can exist with all of the same values for {{param|RemoteHost}}, {{param|ExternalPort}}, and {{param}}.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="TCP"/>
            <enumeration value="UDP"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InternalClient" access="readWrite">
        <description action="replace">The IP address or DNS host name of an internal client (on the LAN).
Support for an IP address is mandatory.  If {{param}} is specified as an IP address and the LAN device's IP address subsequently changes, the port mapping MUST remain associated with the original IP address.
Support for DNS host names is OPTIONAL.  If {{param}} is specified as a DNS host name and the LAN device's IP address subsequently changes, the port mapping MUST remain associated with this LAN device.  In this case, it is the responsibility of the CPE to maintain the name-to-address mapping in the event of IP address changes.  This can be accomplished, for example, by assigning the DNS host name via use of DHCP option 12 (Host Name) or option 81 (FQDN).  Note that the ACS can learn the host name associated with a given LAN device via the ''Hosts'' table ({{object|InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.{i}.Hosts}}).
Read access to this parameter MUST always return the exact value that was last set by the ACS.  For example, if the internal client is set to a DNS host name, it MUST read back as a DNS host name and not as an IP address.
{{empty}} indicates an unconfigured {{param}}. If this parameter is unconfigured, this port mapping MUST NOT be operational.
It MUST be possible to set the {{param}} to the broadcast IP address 255.255.255.255 for UDP mappings. This is to enable multiple NAT clients to use the same well-known port simultaneously.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PortMappingDescription" access="readWrite">
        <description>User-readable description of this port mapping.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string/>
          <default type="object" value=""/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANConnectionDevice.{i}.WANPPPConnection.{i}.Stats." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">This object contains statistics for all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.  The contents of this object SHOULD be identical for each such connection.
This object is intended only for ''WANConnectionDevice''s that can support an Ethernet-layer on this interface (e.g., ''PPPoE'', ''IPoE'').</description>
      <parameter name="EthernetBytesSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes transmitted, including framing characters, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetBytesReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of bytes received, including framing characters, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets transmitted over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The total number of packets which were received over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetErrorsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets that could not be transmitted because of errors, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetErrorsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets that contained errors preventing them from being deliverable, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetUnicastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address, including those that were discarded or not sent, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetUnicastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were not addressed to a multicast or broadcast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetDiscardPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of outbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being transmitted, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetDiscardPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of inbound packets which were chosen to be discarded even though no errors had been detected to prevent their being deliverable, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.  One possible reason for discarding such a packet could be to free up buffer space. 
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetMulticastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission, including those that were discarded or not sent, which were addressed to a multicast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetMulticastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a multicast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetBroadcastPacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets requested for transmission, including those that were discarded or not sent, which were addressed to a broadcast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetBroadcastPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of received packets which were addressed to a broadcast address, over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="EthernetUnknownProtoPacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The total number of packets which were discarded because of an unknown or unsupported protocol, received over all connections within the same ''WANConnectionDevice'' that share a common MAC address.
The value of this counter MAY be reset to zero when the CPE is rebooted.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANDSLConnectionManagement." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description action="replace">This object is intended for a CPE with a DSL modem WAN interface.
Note - This object was originally created to allow ''WANConnection'' devices and services to be added dynamically in the IGD object model in TR-064 because UPnP Device Architecture 1.0 did not contain this capability natively.  Because in TR-069 objects can be created and removed using the AddObject and DeleteObject RPCs, ''WANConnection'' interfaces can be managed using these TR-069 mechanisms directly.  Therefore, unlike the TR-064 equivalent, the {{object|ConnectionService}} table within this object is Read-Only in the TR-069 ''InternetGatewayDevice'' data model context.
This object is OBSOLETED because it serves no purpose.</description>
      <parameter name="ConnectionServiceNumberOfEntries" access="readOnly" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="append">This parameter is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.  The CPE MAY return a value of 0 for this parameter, regardless of the number of connection services, in which case no {{object|ConnectionService}} instances will exist.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANDSLConnectionManagement.ConnectionService.{i}." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="unbounded" numEntriesParameter="ConnectionServiceNumberOfEntries">
      <description action="append">This object is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.</description>
      <uniqueKey>
        <parameter ref="WANConnectionService"/>
      </uniqueKey>
      <parameter name="WANConnectionDevice" access="readOnly" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="append">This parameter is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="WANConnectionService" access="readOnly" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="replace">Specifies a WAN connection object associated with this connection instance.  The content is the full hierarchical parameter name of the layer 3 connection object.  Example: ''InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.1.WANConnectionDevice.2.WANPPPConnection.1''.
This parameter is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DestinationAddress" access="readOnly" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="append">The "PVC:" or "SVC:" prefix is part of the parameter value and MUST be followed by 0 or 1 space characters.  For example, possible values for this parameter are "PVC:8/23" or "PVC: 0/35".
This parameter is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="256"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LinkType" access="readOnly" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="replace">Link Type of the ''WANConnectionDevice'' entry.  One of Link Types as described in ''WANDSLLinkConfig''.
This parameter is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="16"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ConnectionType" access="readOnly" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="append">This parameter is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="16"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Name" access="readOnly" status="obsoleted">
        <description action="append">This parameter is OBSOLETED because it is within an OBSOLETED object.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="32"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANDSLInterfaceConfig." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object models physical layer properties specific to a single physical connection of a DSL modem used for Internet access on a CPE.  This object is required for a CPE with a DSL modem WAN interface, and is exclusive of any other ''WAN*InterfaceConfig'' object within a given ''WANDevice'' instance.</description>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables the link.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Status" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The {{enum|Error}} value MAY be used by the CPE to indicate a locally defined error condition.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Up"/>
            <enumeration value="Initializing"/>
            <enumeration value="EstablishingLink"/>
            <enumeration value="NoSignal"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UpstreamCurrRate" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, it MUST have the value 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DownstreamCurrRate" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, it MUST have the value 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UpstreamMaxRate" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note:  This parameter is related to the G.997.1 parameter ATTNDRus, which is measured in bits/s.  See ITU-T Recommendation G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DownstreamMaxRate" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note:  This parameter is related to the G.997.1 parameter ATTNDRds, which is measured in bits/s.  See ITU-T Recommendation G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UpstreamNoiseMargin" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The current signal-to-noise ratio margin (expressed in 0.1 dB) in the upstream direction.
Note:  In G.997.1, this parameter is called SNRMus.  See ITU-T Recommendation G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DownstreamNoiseMargin" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The current signal-to-noise ratio margin (expressed in 0.1 dB) in the downstream direction.
Note:  In G.997.1, this parameter is called SNRMds.  See ITU-T Recommendation G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <int/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UpstreamAttenuation" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The current upstream signal loss (expressed in 0.1 dB).</description>
        <syntax>
          <int/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DownstreamAttenuation" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>The current downstream signal loss (expressed in 0.1 dB).</description>
        <syntax>
          <int/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="UpstreamPower" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The current output power at the CPE's DSL interface (expressed in 0.1 dBmV).</description>
        <syntax>
          <int/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DownstreamPower" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">The current received power at the CPE's DSL interface (expressed in 0.1 dBmV).</description>
        <syntax>
          <int/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATURVendor" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, it MUST have the value "00000000".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="8"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATURCountry" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, it MUST have the value "0000".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="4"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCVendor" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, it MUST have the value "00000000".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="8"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCCountry" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, it MUST have the value "0000".</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <size maxLength="4"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TotalStart" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">Number of seconds since the beginning of the period used for collection of ''Total'' statistics.
Statistics SHOULD continue to be accumulated across CPE reboots, though this might not always be possible.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ShowtimeStart" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="replace">Number of seconds since the most recent DSL Showtime - the beginning of the period used for collection of ''Showtime'' statistics.
Showtime is defined as successful completion of the DSL link establishment process.  The ''Showtime'' statistics are those collected since the most recent establishment of the DSL link.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANDSLInterfaceConfig.Stats." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains statistics for a WAN DSL physical interface.</description>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANDSLInterfaceConfig.Stats.Showtime." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains DSL statistics accumulated since the most recent DSL Showtime.</description>
      <parameter name="ReceiveBlocks" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="replace">Number of successfully received blocks since the most recent DSL Showtime, where a block is as defined in RFC 2662 {{bibref|RFC2662}}.
This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TransmitBlocks" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="replace">Number of successfully transmitted blocks since the most recent DSL Showtime, where a block is as defined in RFC 2662 {{bibref|RFC2662}}.
This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="CellDelin" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LinkRetrain" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InitErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not defined in G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InitTimeouts" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Number of initialization timeout errors since the most recent DSL Showtime.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LossOfFraming" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not defined in G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ErroredSecs" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SeverelyErroredSecs" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCFECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="HECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCHECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="CRCErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCCRCErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANDSLInterfaceConfig.Stats.Total." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains DSL total statistics.</description>
      <parameter name="ReceiveBlocks" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="replace">Total number of successfully received blocks, where a block is as defined in RFC 2662 {{bibref|RFC2662}}.
This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="TransmitBlocks" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="replace">Total number of successfully transmitted blocks, where a block is as defined in RFC 2662 {{bibref|RFC2662}}.
This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="CellDelin" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LinkRetrain" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not available at either the G or the S/T interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InitErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not defined in G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="InitTimeouts" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Total number of initialization timeout errors.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="LossOfFraming" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny" status="deprecated">
        <description action="append">This parameter is DEPRECATED because it is not defined in G.997.1.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ErroredSecs" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="SeverelyErroredSecs" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="FECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCFECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="HECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCHECErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="CRCErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="ATUCCRCErrors" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description action="append">Note: This parameter is OPTIONAL at the G and S/T interfaces in G.997.1 Amendment 1.  If the parameter is implemented but no value is available, its value MUST be 4294967295 (the maximum for its data type).</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANEthernetInterfaceConfig." access="readOnly" minEntries="0" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object models physical layer properties specific to a single Ethernet physical connection used for Internet access on a CPE.  This object is required for a CPE with an Ethernet WAN interface, and is exclusive of any other ''WAN*InterfaceConfig'' object within a given ''WANDevice'' instance.  Note that this object is not related to the Ethernet protocol layer sometimes used in associated with a DSL connection.</description>
      <parameter name="Enable" access="readWrite">
        <description>Enables or disables this interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <boolean/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="Status" access="readOnly">
        <description action="append">{{enum}}
The {{enum|Error}} value MAY be used by the CPE to indicate a locally defined error condition.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Up"/>
            <enumeration value="NoLink"/>
            <enumeration value="Error" optional="true"/>
            <enumeration value="Disabled"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MACAddress" access="readOnly">
        <description>The physical address of the interface.</description>
        <syntax>
          <dataType ref="MACAddress"/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="MaxBitRate" access="readWrite">
        <description>The maximum upstream and downstream bit rate available to this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="10"/>
            <enumeration value="100"/>
            <enumeration value="1000"/>
            <enumeration value="10000"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="DuplexMode" access="readWrite">
        <description>The duplex mode available to this connection.</description>
        <syntax>
          <string>
            <enumeration value="Half"/>
            <enumeration value="Full"/>
            <enumeration value="Auto"/>
          </string>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
    <object xmlns:dm="urn:broadband-forum-org:cwmp:datamodel-1-4" name="InternetGatewayDevice.WANDevice.{i}.WANEthernetInterfaceConfig.Stats." access="readOnly" minEntries="1" maxEntries="1">
      <description>This object contains statistics for an Ethernet WAN interface on a CPE device.</description>
      <parameter name="BytesSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Total number of bytes sent over the interface since the CPE was last reset.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="BytesReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Total number of bytes received over the interface since the CPE was last reset.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PacketsSent" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Total number of packets sent over the interface since the CPE was last reset.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="PacketsReceived" access="readOnly" activeNotify="canDeny">
        <description>Total number of packets received over the interface since the CPE was last reset.</description>
        <syntax>
          <unsignedInt/>
        </syntax>
      </parameter>
    </object>
  </model>
</urn:document>